<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Briefing Room | The White House Scroll to Top</title>
    <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/whitehouse/briefing-room" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <description>Briefing Room | The White House Scroll to Top - Powered by RSSHub</description>
    <generator>RSSHub</generator>
    <webMaster>contact@rsshub.app (RSSHub)</webMaster>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 21:42:42 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <ttl>180</ttl>
    <item>
      <title>May 2024 Visitor Logs Records Posted</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="container"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today the White House released visitor log records generated in May 2024. This set includes 87,040 records, bringing the total number of records posted to 1,562,536&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These records were posted pursuant to the White House’s policy to voluntarily disclose visitor log records. This release is consistent with the Biden-Harris Administration’s commitment to becoming the first administration to post visitor log records from its first full year in office.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the policy, read our &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/voluntary-disclosure/"&gt;voluntary disclosure policy&lt;/a&gt;. To view visitor log records, view our &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/disclosures/visitor-logs/"&gt;disclosure page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;###&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/disclosures/2024/09/04/may-2024-visitor-logs-records-posted/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/disclosures/2024/09/04/may-2024-visitor-logs-records-posted/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 21:01:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statement from President Joe Biden on Shooting at Apalachee High School in Georgia</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="container"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Jill and I are mourning the deaths of those whose lives were cut short due to more senseless gun violence and thinking of all of the survivors whose lives are forever changed. What should have been a joyous back-to-school season in Winder, Georgia, has now turned into another horrific reminder of how gun violence continues to tear our communities apart. Students across the country are learning how to duck and cover instead of how to read and write. We cannot continue to accept this as normal.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We are closely coordinating with officials at the federal, state and local level, and are grateful for the first responders who brought the suspect into custody and prevented further loss of life.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ending this gun violence epidemic is personal to me. It’s why I signed into law the Bipartisan Safer Communities Act – the most meaningful gun safety bill in decades – and have announced dozens of gun safety executive actions. I also established the first-ever White House Office of Gun Violence Prevention, overseen by Vice President Harris. We’ve made significant progress, but this crisis requires even more.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After decades of inaction, Republicans in Congress must finally say ‘enough is enough’ and work with Democrats to pass common-sense gun safety legislation. We must ban assault weapons and high-capacity magazines once again, require safe storage of firearms, enact universal background checks, and end immunity for gun manufacturers. These measures will not bring those who were tragically killed today back, but it will help prevent more tragic gun violence from ripping more families apart.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;###&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/09/04/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-shooting-at-apalachee-high-school-in-georgia/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/09/04/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-shooting-at-apalachee-high-school-in-georgia/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 18:19:29 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FACT SHEET: Biden-⁠Harris Administration Announces Additional Actions to Drive Academic Success for all Students</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="container"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Biden-Harris Administration believes that public education is the bedrock of our democracy and the foundation of opportunity in our country—and that every young person should have the chance to learn, grow, and pursue their dreams. Since Day One, the Biden-Harris Administration has focused on improving academic achievement, increasing student attendance and engagement, and building communities where all students feel they belong and can thrive. That’s why the Biden-Harris Administration made the single-largest investment in K-12 education in history—and it is delivering results, including &lt;a href="https://caldercenter.org/sites/default/files/CALDER%20WP%20301-0624.pdf"&gt;student achievement gains&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;A Harvard and Stanford &lt;a href="https://educationrecoveryscorecard.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/June2024ERS-Report.pdf"&gt;study&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://educationrecoveryscorecard.org/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/June2024ERS-Report.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;, for example&lt;/a&gt;, for example, examined outcomes in districts that received large amounts of federal COVID-19 relief funding, which ranged from approximately $4,000 to more than $13,000 per student, and found that these investments will &lt;a href="https://www.hoover.org/sites/default/files/research/docs/Hanushek-Strauss_WebreadyPDF_240229.pdf"&gt;pay for&lt;/a&gt; itself in &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.3386/w30701"&gt;increased&lt;/a&gt; earnings for students who benefit, with particularly large impacts for students in schools with high rates of poverty. These investments not only improve academic achievement, but other student outcomes. Another &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/qje/article/131/1/157/2461148"&gt;economic study&lt;/a&gt; shows that a 10% increase in per student spending each year for all 12 years of public school leads to about 7% higher wages in adulthood, with more pronounced effects for students from low-income backgrounds.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;As students across the country head back to school, the Biden-Harris Administration is working to make sure America’s schools have the resources and supports they need to continue their important progress. Working together, at the federal, state, and local level, we must all double-down on strengthening reading and math skills; increasing student attendance and engagement; providing afterschool and expanded learning programs; and increasing access to intensive tutoring. We must also provide teachers and school leaders with evidence-based preparation, development, coaching, and resources to support student academic success and literacy and math and their overall well-being, which is foundational to that success.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;As part of our ongoing commitment to support student success, today we are announcing the following Administration actions&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awarding &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://oese.ed.gov/offices/office-of-discretionary-grants-support-services/well-rounded-education-programs/striving-readers-comprehensive-literacy-srcl-formula-grants-84-371a-for-state-literacy-teams/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$149 million to support states in implementing evidence-based reading interventions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;, including efforts to ensure every child is reading fluently by third grade.&lt;/strong&gt; The U.S. Department of Education’s Comprehensive Literacy State Development grant program supports states in creating comprehensive literacy programs and providing professional development to advance literacy skills, including pre-literacy skills, reading, and writing, for children and youth, focusing on underserved students, including students from low-income backgrounds, English learners, and children with disabilities. For example, Ohio will partner with state colleges and universities to better prepare educators to deliver evidence-based literacy instruction, and Montana will use funds to expand reading instructional skills for educators in rural communities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Awarding &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://oese.ed.gov/offices/office-of-formula-grants/school-support-and-accountability/competitive-grants-for-state-assessments/"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;$30 million to support comprehensive assessment systems that inform teaching and support learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;. &lt;/strong&gt;The U.S. Department of Education’s Competitive Grants for State Assessments program supports high-quality state assessment systems that measure student achievement and progress using multiple measures and gives insight into student learning, helping to inform instruction and support student achievement. For example, Nebraska will use funds to support English Learners by making assessment data more usable and actionable for educators as they design instruction.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issuing new &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://oese.ed.gov/files/2024/09/School-Improvement-Guidance-public-comment.pdf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;school improvement guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; focused on evidence-based practices to support students and educators and accelerate academic achievement. &lt;/strong&gt;To further support states and districts in their efforts to increase student success, the U.S. Department of Education is issuing school improvement guidance to support effective implementation of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act. The guidance provides examples of evidence-based approaches to support teaching and learning and drive student achievement. This includes addressing chronic absenteeism (for example, through early warning systems and improved family engagement, like home visits and effective parent communication such as texting), and providing high-quality tutoring (in small groups, 2-3 times per week by a well-prepared tutor, during the school day, and aligned with classroom instruction), and afterschool, expanded, and summer learning programs. This draft guidance is open for public comment until October 4, 2024. The Department will consider this community input and issue updated guidance by the end of the year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Releasing a new &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://members.nces.ed.gov/blogs/ncee/post/evidence-based-strategies-for-improving-student-literacy-and-teaching-mathematics-in-grades-pk-9"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;resource for educators&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; on evidence-based strategies for increasing student literacy and math achievement.&lt;/strong&gt; The Institute of Education Sciences is releasing a resource for educators on instructional strategies for increasing student success in literacy and math. Each resource includes concrete practices that can be used by teachers from early grades to high school, and provides links to additional resources that can support learning at home.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To support states, districts, schools, and families in addressing chronic absenteeism and increase student engagement, the Administration is:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calling on Governors and state education leaders to create statewide student data systems that provide chronic absenteeism-related data for all schools that are actionable, help target interventions, and drive improvement. &lt;/strong&gt;The Administration encourages all state leaders to ensure that every school district in their state has the real-time data they need to identify and reduce chronic absenteeism and improve student success. States including Alabama, Connecticut, Indiana, and Rhode Island have developed innovative statewide student information systems to help increase student attendance. At a minimum, state systems are encouraged to provide:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to the public, up-to-date rates of chronic absenteeism and whether rates are declining or increasing;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;to educators, real-time, school-level data that enables them to identify the root causes of chronic absenteeism, select the appropriate interventions, target resources, and measure effectiveness; and&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;to parents and families, real-time information on their child’s attendance.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Calling on industry vendors that provide student information systems to improve the availability and utility of student attendance data. &lt;/strong&gt;This includes making attendance data available to states and districts at no additional cost; not charging districts to access, securely export, or display their own data; and adopting industry aligned data standards or practices for student attendance data that allows for interoperability between the modules that states and districts use, between vendors, and between districts that may use different data systems.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To support these efforts, this year, the Department of Education will issue a resource for state leaders highlighting different state approaches to creating and implementing data systems to address chronic absenteeism along with recommendations for states and local leaders.&lt;/strong&gt; The guide will also include information on how federal funding can be used to support these efforts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Founding the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Student&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Attendance and Engagement Solutions Network&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, part of the &lt;a href="https://www.partnershipstudentsuccess.org/"&gt;National Partnership for Student Success&lt;/a&gt; (NPSS), a partnership among the U.S. Department of Education, AmeriCorps, and the Johns Hopkins University &lt;a href="https://new.every1graduates.org/meeting-the-chronic-absenteeism-challenge-what-do-we-know/"&gt;Everyone Graduates Center&lt;/a&gt;. The Network supports school districts and states in their efforts to reduce chronic absenteeism, increase student engagement, and enhance prevention strategies for the 2024-25 academic year and beyond. To date, almost 200 school districts across 43 states and eight state education agencies, in total representing more than 11,000 schools and 7.2 million students, have joined the network to learn from each other about how to improve attendance and engagement. The Network is open for districts and states to join. More information on the network and how to join can be found &lt;a href="https://www.partnershipstudentsuccess.org/attendance-solutions-network/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Releasing a &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www2.ed.gov/programs/DOTandEDJointResourceTransportationSept2024.pdf"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;joint resource&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; by the U.S. Departments of Education and Transportation highlighting ways to provide safe, reliable transit options to get young people to and from school and support everyday student attendance.&lt;/strong&gt; Many students miss school because of transportation issues, especially in vulnerable communities. To address this issue, transit agencies, school districts, and local and state government leaders can work together to improve transit options for families, including through offering free or reduced transit fares, expanding safe routes to school, and creating a “walking or bike bus”. This resource includes strategies to support students and families in getting to and from school at low or no cost, and federal funding available to support these efforts through the Departments of Education and Transportation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Releasing, this month, a joint resource for parents by the U.S. Departments of Education and Agriculture on how healthy school meals support regular attendance.&lt;/strong&gt; This resource provides information that schools can use in engaging parents and caregivers on how school meals bolster everyday student attendance and support healthy growth and development and how to access programs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Launching the “Attendance Champions Challenge” to hear directly from young people on creative solutions to address chronic absenteeism. &lt;/strong&gt;The Challenge, hosted on challenge.gov, will encourage state and local leaders to directly engage young people (ages 13-19) in sharing barriers to regular school attendance and proposing viable, creative solutions to support their attendance and engagement. The Challenge is open until November 29th and more information can be found at &lt;a href="https://www.challenge.gov/?challenge=attendance-champions"&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Providing parents with&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.healthychildren.org/English/ages-stages/gradeschool/school/Pages/When-to-Keep-Your-Child-Home-from-School.aspx"&gt; &lt;strong&gt;resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; on navigating &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/orr/school-preparedness/infection-prevention/when-sick.html"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;whether to send kids to school&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt; when they are experiencing health symptoms. &lt;/strong&gt;The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and &lt;a href="https://www.attendanceworks.org/resources/health-handouts-for-families/"&gt;external organizations&lt;/a&gt; are releasing resources on how to support consistent school attendance, while also &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/vaccines/keepitthatway.html"&gt;preventing spread&lt;/a&gt; of illness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition to these actions by the Administration, a number of organizations have taken action to tackle absenteeism, as previewed during the &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/05/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-new-actions-and-resources-for-increasing-student-attendance-and-engagement-as-part-of-the-white-house-every-day-counts-summit/"&gt;White House Every Day Counts Summit&lt;/a&gt;. These actions include a &lt;a href="https://www.adcouncil.org/learn-with-us/ad-council-research-institute/chronic-student-absenteeism"&gt;messaging toolkit&lt;/a&gt; for states, districts, and educators based on new research around effectively communicating with parents to increase student attendance, developed by &lt;strong&gt;the Ad Council Research Institute (ACRI)&lt;/strong&gt;, with support from&lt;strong&gt; Overdeck Family Foundation&lt;/strong&gt;, available on September 10&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;. Information on additional actions by organizations is available &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/05/15/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-new-actions-and-resources-for-increasing-student-attendance-and-engagement-as-part-of-the-white-house-every-day-counts-summit/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;These resources build on the previous Administration actions to promote academic achievement and student success, including:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Securing $130 billion for the largest-ever investment in public education through state and district funding in the American Rescue Plan (ARP). &lt;/strong&gt;ARP has been used to help schools safely reopen, and address the academic, mental health, and other needs of students. ARP funding has put more teachers in our classrooms and more support staff in our schools; expanded high-dosage tutoring; led to record expansion of summer and after-school programs; improved HVAC systems; and increased access to a wide range of student supports. The most recent data shows that states and districts have allocated more than $70 billion to activities that address students’ academic, social, and emotional needs, including tutoring, afterschool, and summer learning, and research is showing that these &lt;a href="https://caldercenter.org/sites/default/files/CALDER%20WP%20301-0624.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;investments&lt;/a&gt; are &lt;a href="https://educationrecoveryscorecard.org/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener"&gt;working&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enabling states to continue investing pandemic relief funds into academic achievement efforts in the 2024-25 school year and focus remaining resources on improving outcomes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;The Department issued a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://oese.ed.gov/files/2024/01/ARP-Liquidation-Extension-Letter-1.9.24-final-for-signature-v3.pdf"&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://oese.ed.gov/files/2024/01/Updated-Technical-FAQs-for-Liquidation-Extensions-1.9.24-v-2-for-posting.pdf"&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/a&gt;, and a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://view.officeapps.live.com/op/view.aspx?src=https%3A%2F%2Foese.ed.gov%2Ffiles%2F2024%2F01%2FARP-ESSER-EANS-Liquidation-Extension-Request-1.10.24-v3.xlsx&amp;amp;wdOrigin=BROWSELINK"&gt;template&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to support States and provide&amp;nbsp;a critical pathway to continue to use ARP dollars in the 2024-2025 school year, including on evidence-based academic and other student supports.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fully enforcing the ARP maintenance of equity provisions to ensure that States maintain their own levels of education spending, especially for communities with high rates of poverty.&lt;/strong&gt; Under the Department’s robust implementation of these fiscal equity provisions, 48 States, Puerto Rico, and the District of Columbia safeguarded funding in communities with high rates of poverty and drove almost $800 million to under-resourced schools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;hr class="wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity"&gt;



&lt;p&gt;[i]&amp;nbsp;The White House does not endorse any nonfederal entity, product, service, or publication. Links to websites and resources outside the U.S. Federal Government are being provided as a convenience and for informational purposes only; they do not constitute an endorsement or an approval by the White House of any of the products, services or opinions of the corporation or organization or individual. The White House bears no responsibility for the accuracy, legality or content of the external site or for that of subsequent links. Contact the external site for answers to questions regarding its content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/09/04/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-additional-actions-to-drive-academic-success-for-all-students/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/09/04/fact-sheet-biden-harris-administration-announces-additional-actions-to-drive-academic-success-for-all-students/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 14:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remarks by Second Gentleman Douglas Emhoff at the National Vigil for the Hostages at Adas Israel Congregation</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="container"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Adas Israel Congregation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;As Prepared for Delivery&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SECOND GENTLEMAN DOUGLAS EMHOFF: Thank you, Ted, and thank you to the many leaders here tonight from the AJC, ADL, JCRC, Federation, Washington Hebrew, and all the others who are here.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is thanks in part to the help of some of these organizations and others we have a National Strategy to Combat Antisemitism, an effort that is even more urgent today than when we announced it in May of 2023.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It is good to be together this evening. There is comfort in community.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But standing on this bimah, I can only be direct: This is hard. I feel raw. I’m gutted.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I know you are too.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I haven’t been able to stop thinking about Hersh and his parents, or about the five others and their families.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;While I’m here as the Second Gentleman of the United States — and the first-ever Jewish White House principal — in this moment I’m here as a congregant, as a mourner, as a Jew who feels connected to all of you and grateful for the guidance of our wonderful rabbis, Aaron and Lauren.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;They have become confidants and advisors. We’ve talked a lot about my own faith journey – something Kamala has encouraged in me.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Among the many things they helped me find was my voice.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At this moment, in light of the retraumatizing tragedy of this weekend, speaking here — even though this is hard — is a way I can use that voice.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The Vice President and I spoke this weekend to Hersh’s parents, Rachel and Jon.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;It was not the first time we had spoken to them.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;She had met with them several times, and I met with them just a couple weeks ago.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But this call, of course, was different.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I wish you all could have heard that phone call.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We expressed our condolences even though we know those words were not enough.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We talked about Hersh as a person, as their son, and just who he was – a joyful young man.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Their souls were torn apart, just like the garments we tear in mourning.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And yet, they were comforting us. They were asking about the latest in the negotiations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;They were asking how we can use this terrible moment to make progress.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;They told the Vice President that they don’t want Hersh’s death to be in vain.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;They spoke with grace and compassion.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Part of Rachel and Jon’s world had just ended, and they somehow are still looking forward and looking out for others.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Rachel and Jon spoke about the need to bring all the hostages home and end the suffering in Gaza, something the Vice President is working on every single day.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As the President and Vice President have said, Hamas is responsible for killing Hersh, Ori, Carmel, Alexander, Almog, Eden, and too many others — and Hamas’s leaders will pay for these crimes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You’ve all seen the pieces of tape that Rachel and Jon have been wearing over their hearts throughout this dark year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At Hersh’s funeral yesterday, they still wore the tape marking the number of days the hostages have been in captivity: 332.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I saw that and thought: the count was never about their son alone.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Jon and Rachel’s hearts have room to hold everyone.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;They are not giving up, and neither can we.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Not on this 333rd day.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Not ever.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Not until every hostage is reunited with their family.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Why does Hersh’s loss feel so personal to us? Because Rachel and Jon made sure we knew him – just like they made sure on our phone call over the weekend.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In relating their love for their son over and over again — in reliving their pain in every place and platform they could — they planted their love for Hersh in all of us.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Something we saw in so many stories from that tragic day is the love of parents and the strength of families.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There were stories like the grandfather who drove hours to rescue his son and grandchildren who were hiding in a bomb shelter.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;There were many more stories of sacrifice that ended differently.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That love, multiplied, is what makes our community who we are and what makes us strong.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;How you feel right now is how I feel. And how we all feel is something the Kamala hears directly from me.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Every time something else terrible happens — in Israel, in Gaza, around the world, or here at home — it’s devastating all over again.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I share what I’m feeling with the Vice President – as my partner, as my wife. She knows. She gets it. She cares. She’s committed.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Hersh’s loss feels personal to the two of us. We’re both grieving.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Many of you saw Rachel and Jon speak to the country last month in their hometown of Chicago.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As they were preparing for that moment, they wanted to tell the story of Hersh’s heroism, the peace he believed in, the friends he defended&amp;nbsp;during the attack, the seven grenades he threw out of the bomb shelter until the eighth one killed his best friend and took Hersh’s hand.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But here’s the thing: that’s not all they wanted to say on the national stage.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Even as they shared the story of their only son, they also felt an obligation to tell the stories and numbers of October 7th to those who might not have already known them: the innocent, peace-loving festival-goers who were killed,&amp;nbsp;the horrific sexual violence the hostages — Americans, Israelis, and others; Jews and non-Jews — who are still being held.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Think about that: after nearly 11 months of being consumed by this hell, they were somehow clear-eyed enough to understand that there were others out there who don’t know this story or don’t believe it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In our community, what happened on October 7th is already seared into our souls. &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We think about the attacks and the victims and the hostages every day.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;If I say just “Nova,” or “the tunnels” or “Hersh,” you all know immediately what I mean. No further descriptions necessary.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;What Rachel and Jon know is that unless we tell the story again and again, we have no hope of “never again.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;As Aaron and Lauren can tell you better than I can, bearing witness is a fundamental chorus of Judaism, from Mount Sinai to the Passover Seder to the Holocaust to October 7th.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Hamas’s cold-blooded execution of six hostages, including an American, who could have been so close to coming home — reminds us that the trauma of October 7 has still not gone away.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The time to bring them home is now.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That is why President Biden and Vice President Harris are working around the clock to get a hostage-and-ceasefire deal done.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I don’t know that I would be as strong as Rachel and Jon if I were in their shoes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But right now, we all need to find that strength.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Thank you for the opportunity to share this experience with you, to mourn with you, to pray alongside you for the return of all the hostages, and to honor those we’ve lost.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;May their memories be a blessing. May their deaths never be in vain. And may we all know peace soon.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;# # #&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/09/03/remarks-by-second-gentleman-douglas-emhoff-at-the-national-vigil-for-the-hostages-at-adas-israel-congregation/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/09/03/remarks-by-second-gentleman-douglas-emhoff-at-the-national-vigil-for-the-hostages-at-adas-israel-congregation/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 03:59:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Statement from President Joe Biden on Russian Attack on Poltava, Ukraine</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="container"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Earlier today, Russian missiles struck a military training facility and a hospital in Ukraine—killing more than 50 people and injuring dozens more. I condemn this deplorable attack in the strongest possible terms.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This assault is a tragic reminder of Putin’s ongoing and outrageous attempts to break the will of a free people. But for two and a half years, the people of Ukraine have stood unbowed. And the United States will continue stand with them—including providing the air defense systems and capabilities they need to protect their country.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake: Russia will not prevail in this war. The people of Ukraine will prevail. And on this tragic day, and every day, the United States stands with them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;###&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/09/03/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-russian-attack-on-poltava-ukraine/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/statements-releases/2024/09/03/statement-from-president-joe-biden-on-russian-attack-on-poltava-ukraine/</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 01:20:11 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On-the-Record Press Gaggle by White House National Security Communications Advisor John Kirby</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="container"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;Via Teleconference&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;12:25 P.M. EDT&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR:&amp;nbsp; Hey, everyone.&amp;nbsp; Hope everyone enjoyed the long weekend.&amp;nbsp; Kirby has a few words here at the top, and then we’ll get into as many questions as we can.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; Hey, everybody.&amp;nbsp; Thanks for joining.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;First, on the Middle East.&amp;nbsp; As you all know, on Saturday, in a tunnel in Gaza, Israeli forces recovered six bodies of hostages that were held by Hamas, including an American citizen, Hersh Goldberg-Polin.&amp;nbsp; He and five others were executed.&amp;nbsp; Hamas is responsible for their deaths.&amp;nbsp; And as the President said, Hamas leaders will pay for their crimes.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;As you know, the President also had a chance to speak with Hersh’s parents, Jon and Rachel, and — as did the Vice President — and they grieve with them and with all the families of everyone killed.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Yesterday, the President and Vice President had a chance to meet in the White House Situation Room with the U.S. hostage deal negotiation team to talk about next steps on our ongoing effort to secure the release of the hostages and to hold Hamas leaders fully accountable.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;As for the status of those talks, over the past couple of days, we’ve heard a lot from Israel, we’ve heard some from Hamas, and we continue to consult with our co-mediators, Qatar and Egypt.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Just, again, to restate it: We’re working on a proposal that will secure the release of the remaining hostages and will include massive and immediate relief for the people of Gaza, and also result in a stoppage of the fighting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Now, I’ve seen some press reporting out there about “take it or leave it” and “final proposal” and “text this” and “text that.”&amp;nbsp; All I’m telling you is our team is still working on trying to get this to closure, to try to conclude a deal that achieves all of those three things.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And I’m sure you’re all curious as to what that proposal says and what’s in it, and I’m sure you’re also not going to be surprised by the fact that I’m not going to get into that detail.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;What I can tell you is we are still actively working on this.&amp;nbsp; We are still in constant consultations with Qatar, Egypt, and Israel.&amp;nbsp; And of course, Qatar and Egypt are in touch with Hamas.&amp;nbsp; And we’re going to do what we can to get it done.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;I can’t tell you what the timeline looks like.&amp;nbsp; I can’t tell you, if we get it done, exactly what every little — every little paragraph and context of the final proposal would look like.&amp;nbsp; All I can tell you is those are the three goals, and that’s what we’re still driving at, and we’re still actively engaged in the effort.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;The President himself is personally involved in working with our team and in working with leaders around the world to secure this deal, and that’s what we’re focused on.&amp;nbsp; And the killing over the weekend just underscores the sense of urgency that we have to have in order to get it to closure.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;If I can switch to Venezuela.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;The United States joins several of our international partners in condemning the unjustified arrest warrant of Edmundo Gonzalez in Venezuela for allegedly inciting violence — which, of course, is not accurate.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;This is just another example of Mr. Maduro’s efforts to maintain power by force and to refuse to recognize that Mr.&amp;nbsp; Gonzalez won the most votes on the 28th of July.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;So, in coordination with those partners, we’re considering a range of options to demonstrate to Mr. Maduro and his representatives that their actions in Venezuela will have consequences.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Now, I don’t have anything to announce today, but as you’ve seen, we’ve already enforced and calibrated our sanctions towards Venezuela in light of overall U.S. interests and the actions and non-actions that are taken by Maduro and his representatives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;In fact, just yesterday, the U.S. Department of Justice announced the seizure of an aircraft used by Mr. Maduro and his representatives, based on sanctions and export control violations that were already in place.&amp;nbsp; This action taken by Justice was really done in the overall direction of our broader bilateral engagement with Venezuela.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And then, quickly on Ukraine.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Sadly, we have to yet again offer our deepest condolences to the people of Ukraine after another massive Russian strike, this time in a town called Poltova [sic] — I’m sorry, Poltava — which killed more than 40 people and wounded at least 180 others.&amp;nbsp; Just another horrific reminder of the extent of Mr.&amp;nbsp; Putin’s brutality towards the people of Ukraine and the manner in which he’s trying to punish them for his own invasion of that country, going after critical infrastructure and trying to make it harder just for them to live and to pursue livelihoods.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;As President Biden has made clear, our support for Ukraine remains unshakable, and we’re going to continue to be focused on strengthening their military and their air defenses against these kinds of assaults and attacks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;As you saw just 10 days ago, we announced yet another drawdown of military assistance.&amp;nbsp; That included ammunition for HIMARS systems, counter-drone equipment, munitions, Javelin anti-tank and anti-armor systems.&amp;nbsp; And there will be more coming in coming weeks.&amp;nbsp; So we’re going to continue to stand by Ukraine as they try to defend themselves against these sorts of attacks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;With that, we can take some questions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR:&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp; Our first question will go to Zeke with the AP.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Thanks, John, for doing this.&amp;nbsp; A couple weeks ago, you had said that the U.S. was putting forward a new bridging proposal to close the remaining gaps between the two sides.&amp;nbsp; Is the proposal that’s being developed this week, the President is actively engaged in, is that a new proposal or is that just a refinement of what has already been on the table now for some weeks and, really, in essence, some months?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And then, separately, do you have any specific reaction to the Israeli Prime Minister’s comments yesterday, sort of drawing the line on holding the Philadelphi Corridor?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And then, can you offer a little bit more clarity on the President’s comments that Netanyahu isn’t doing enough to get this deal?&amp;nbsp; Is a deal possible while Netanyahu remains in power?&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; The answer to your third question is: Yes, of course, there’s a deal possible.&amp;nbsp; And the President wouldn’t be personally engaged the way he is and he wouldn’t have taken the time over the weekend to meet with his team if he didn’t believe that that was, in fact, an outcome that we can achieve.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;I won’t get into the details of the proposal that we are working on, but we continue to work on it.&amp;nbsp; And it won’t come as a surprise to anybody that when you’re involved in negotiations, particularly at high stakes like this, there’s a lot of back-and-forth, and there’s amendments offered and there’s amendments rejected, and there’s text that changes from time to time.&amp;nbsp; That work continues, and I’m just not going to get into the details of what it looks like or what it may look like if we’re successful.&amp;nbsp; But, yes, absolutely, it’s possible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And again, I think — not that we didn’t have a sense of urgency before; we certainly did — but the killings over the weekend, the executions is the only way to put it, just underscores for us how important it is to keep that work alive and keep going.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;I’m not going to get into a debate with the Prime Minister of what he said over the weekend about the Philadelphi Corridor.&amp;nbsp; The deal itself, the proposal, including the bridging proposal that we started working with — you guys know this; I’m not telling you anything that isn’t out there publicly — included the removal of Israeli Defense Forces from all densely populated areas, and that includes those areas along that corridor.&amp;nbsp; That’s the proposal that Israel had agreed to.&amp;nbsp; And again, we’re going to continue to work on this as hard as we can.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR:&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp; Our next question will go to Steve Holland with Reuters.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; John, what’s the strategy behind referring to this as a “final proposal”?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; I’m just — I’m not using that phrase, Steve, so I can’t — I can’t speak to what strategy might be in place.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (Inaudible.)&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; Well, I’m not using that phrase.&amp;nbsp; And there is a — there is a proposal we’re working on.&amp;nbsp; It is still being negotiated, which means that the sides are still talking about the text itself.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;But we believe — as I said to Zeke, we believe that we can get there.&amp;nbsp; We believe we can close this.&amp;nbsp; And we absolutely have to do it with as much speed as possible, especially given what happened over the weekend.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; And we’ve seen a number of protests in Israel in response to the death of the hostages.&amp;nbsp; Are you hoping these protests will put pressure on Netanyahu to do more to try to get a deal?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; Well, I’ll let the Israeli people speak for themselves, Steve.&amp;nbsp; I’m not qualified nor would I get involved in domestic issues there in Israel.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;I think what happened over the weekend should serve as a reminder to everyone how evil Hamas is and how deadly, how lethal the situation is for all those hostages.&amp;nbsp; And it should underscore for everybody, and I think it does — I think it does in Israel; I think it does in the region; it certainly does here, inside the administration and in the United States — how important it is to get this deal in place and to get those hostages released, get them out, get them back with their families, where they belong.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;So, again, I won’t speak to domestic issues in Israel, and I certainly wouldn’t speak for the Israeli people.&amp;nbsp; I can only tell you that, speaking for President Biden, he’s going to stay 110 percent focused on seeing if we can’t get this over the finish line and to do so as soon as humanly possible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Thank you, John.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; Yes, sir.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR:&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp; Our next question will go to Selina with ABC.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Hi, John.&amp;nbsp; Thanks so much for doing this.&amp;nbsp; I know you don’t want to talk about the specifics of this, quote, “final proposal,” but senior administration officials are saying that there could be a possibility, if that fell apart, that the U.S. could walk away from leading these discussions.&amp;nbsp; Is that a feasible reality, of the U.S. walking away?&amp;nbsp; Is there any world where that could happen — you know, just considering the stakes that are at play here for the U.S., considering some of these hostages are American?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; We want to get them all released, Selina.&amp;nbsp; We want to get them released as soon as possible.&amp;nbsp; Today would be a great day to do that.&amp;nbsp; They should never have been taken in the first place by Hamas.&amp;nbsp; And Hamas bears the responsibility for their taking and for the lives that have already been lost and for the health and welfare of those who are still alive.&amp;nbsp; We want to get them out.&amp;nbsp; We want to get them out now.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;I am simply going to refuse to speculate about what might happen or what might not happen as we are involved, as you and I are speaking, in constant consultations to get this deal over the finish line.&amp;nbsp; The less I say, the better on that.&amp;nbsp; And I’m certainly not going to speculate about what might or might not happen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;I’ll tell you what needs to happen.&amp;nbsp; What needs to happen is the deal to get closed.&amp;nbsp; What needs to happen is the hostages to get home.&amp;nbsp; What needs to happen is more humanitarian assistance in.&amp;nbsp; And this deal would provide an extraordinary amount of additional humanitarian assistance to the suffering people of Gaza, the people who are suffering in Gaza because Mr. Sinwar decided to break a ceasefire, a deal that was in existence on the 6th of October.&amp;nbsp; And what needs to happen is an end to the fighting.&amp;nbsp; And that’s what we’re focused on.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; So, just another follow-up.&amp;nbsp; You’ve said these similar remarks before about how this needs to happen, it’s going to happen, we’re close.&amp;nbsp; Why is this time different?&amp;nbsp; Is there a sense that there is a greater sense of urgency that this could actually be achieved?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And number two, the UK is suspending some arms exports to Israel.&amp;nbsp; What is the official White House reaction to that?&amp;nbsp; And does the White House have any plans to follow suit to increase pressure on Israel?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; Yeah, I never said it &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; happen.&amp;nbsp; I’ve said we believe it &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; happen.&amp;nbsp; We believe that we’re close enough, that the gaps are narrow enough that it could happen.&amp;nbsp; And that remains the case today.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And we have always had a sense of urgency about getting this deal — well, I shouldn’t say “always.”&amp;nbsp; Since it was — since the President laid it out there publicly at the end of May, we have had a high sense of urgency to get it over the finish line, and we’ve been working very, very diligently over these last few months to do that.&amp;nbsp; That work will continue.&amp;nbsp; It will continue with the same sense of importance and energy that we’ve been applying to it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;But, certainly, the work is — the importance of that work is now underscored by the brutal execution of these innocent hostages over the weekend, including an American.&amp;nbsp; Those lives were just recently taken.&amp;nbsp; And I’d be lying to you if I said that the work going on yesterday, today, tomorrow, and the days ahead are not going to be informed or shaped or colored by our own grief and sorrow and shock and outrage about what Hamas did.&amp;nbsp; I couldn’t — I couldn’t say that it wouldn’t be.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;So, there has been a sense of urgency; there will continue to be.&amp;nbsp; And, clearly, what happened over the weekend underscores how important it is to get this done as quickly as possible.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;On the UK, every nation can speak for themselves on how and to what degree that they support Israel.&amp;nbsp; I’m certainly not going to comment one way or another on the decisions that our British counterparts made.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;I can just tell you that, number one, we’re going to continue to do we have to do to support Israel’s defensive capabilities; that support continues today.&amp;nbsp; Number two, we have, as I’ve said many times, reviewed individual reports as best we can and talking to the Israelis about individual reports about compliance with international humanitarian law.&amp;nbsp; And as we speak, there’s been no determination by the United States that they have violated international humanitarian law.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR:&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp; Our next question will go to Felicia with the Financial Times.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Hi, John.&amp;nbsp; Thanks.&amp;nbsp; Just to follow up on the UK decision, has there been any conversations between the White House and Number 10 or any other parts of the U.S. or American government about the decision, or any calls to read out?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; No calls to read out since they’ve announced their decision.&amp;nbsp; They did give us a heads up that they were going to — that they had arrived at that decision and were going to announce it.&amp;nbsp; So, we were aware.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; And are you worried that any other — I guess this is maybe the first major Western ally of Israel’s to take this step.&amp;nbsp; Is the U.S. worried that other countries might follow suit?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; I’ll tell you what we’re worried about.&amp;nbsp; We’re worried about getting a deal to get the hostages home.&amp;nbsp; We’re worried about getting more humanitarian assistance in.&amp;nbsp; And we’re worried about finding an end to this conflict.&amp;nbsp; We’re also worried about making sure we can continue to help Israel defend itself against what is clearly, and certainly should be a reminder to everybody about what happened over the weekend, a brutal, evil terrorist organization.&amp;nbsp; That’s what we’re worried about.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;We’ll let other nations decide for themselves if they’re going to support Israel and to what degree.&amp;nbsp; That’s their decision.&amp;nbsp; That’s what sovereignty is all about.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR:&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp; Our next question will go to Karen with the Washington Post.&amp;nbsp; One second.&amp;nbsp; Our computer is malfunctioning.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Karen, you should be able to talk now.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Yeah, you’ve said several times now that the brutal killings over the weekend underscore the importance of getting this deal done.&amp;nbsp; Prime Minister Netanyahu, in his remarks over the weekend, said sort of the opposite, that — he said: What it underscores is that whenever you show flexibility or give something to Hamas, this is what they do, and we’ve shown flexibility thus far and we’re not anymore — basically, he said.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Can you — how do you reconcile those two positions in terms of getting the negotiations completed?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; I’m not going to reconcile those two positions, Karen.&amp;nbsp; That’s not my job.&amp;nbsp; It’s not my place.&amp;nbsp; I speak for this administration and for this President, and he has been rock-solid and consistent in pushing for his team to do everything they can to get this deal in place.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR:&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp; Our next question will go to Tamara Keith with NPR.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Tam, you should be able to unmute yourself.&amp;nbsp; Okay, we will try to come back to you later.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Our next question will go to Barak with Axios.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Hi.&amp;nbsp; Thank you for doing this.&amp;nbsp; John, two questions.&amp;nbsp; First, if we can go back to what the President said yesterday when he said that he doesn’t think Prime Minister Netanyahu is doing enough to get a deal.&amp;nbsp; What did he mean?&amp;nbsp; What do you need Netanyahu to do that he’s not doing?&amp;nbsp; Or what is Netanyahu doing that you think is not constructive for reaching a deal?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And the second thing, to go back to what you said about the Philadelphi Corridor.&amp;nbsp; You said that the proposal includes the removal of IDF from all densely populated areas, including the Philadelphi Corridor.&amp;nbsp; So, just to understand, do you mean during the first phase of the deal?&amp;nbsp; Do you mean during the entire deal?&amp;nbsp; Because in the next phases, all IDF forces need to be removed from the Philadelphi Corridor.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; Right.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; And Netanyahu said yesterday that he will not remove the IDF from the Philadelphi Corridor ever.&amp;nbsp; So he did not speak only about the first phase of the deal; he spoke about it indefinite.&amp;nbsp; So, I’m trying to understand better what exactly is the U.S. position on the issue of the Philadelphi Corridor on phase one of the deal, on phase two of the deal, and going forward.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; Look, it’s all in the proposal, Barak.&amp;nbsp; And you’ve read the proposal, same as me.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Yeah, I know.&amp;nbsp; But, John, the proposal — the last proposal, including the map that the U.S. approved, included the deployment of the IDF along the Philadelphi Corridor.&amp;nbsp; That’s what I’m saying.&amp;nbsp; And not only in densely populated areas.&amp;nbsp; And the U.S. signed off on this map.&amp;nbsp; That’s why I’m asking what’s the exact U.S. position regarding the Philadelphi Corridor.&amp;nbsp; Because I don’t think that the map that the U.S. has agreed on is the same — reflects the same position you just said.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; I’m not going to get into negotiating this thing in public.&amp;nbsp; You know I’m not going to do that.&amp;nbsp; The deal says that they have to remove IDF from all densely populated areas in phase one, and that includes densely populated areas around — or adjacent to the Philadelphi Corridor, or where it intersects with those densely populated areas.&amp;nbsp; That’s what the proposal says.&amp;nbsp; That’s the proposal that was put forth at the end of May.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;I’m not going to get into amendments one way or another that have subsequently been discussed.&amp;nbsp; I’m not going to negotiate this in public one way or the other.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And as for your first question, the President has in numerous conversations with the Prime Minister, as well as our counterparts in Qatar and Egypt, stressed the importance of doing everything we can to actualize, to conclude the proposal that, again, was an Israeli proposal agreed to at the end of May.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And we — he charged his team on Saturday — I’m sorry, over the weekend he charged his team to do everything that they could to see what we can do to get this over the finish line.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;I understand it would be satisfying if I were to give a list of everything everybody should do outside the United States to make that happen, but I hope you can understand I’m not going to do that.&amp;nbsp; We’ve got to find a way to come to closure on this thing.&amp;nbsp; We are close enough that that is possible.&amp;nbsp; We believe that it’s an outcome that can be achieved.&amp;nbsp; But as I’ve said many times: In order to do that, it requires compromise and it requires leadership from everybody.&amp;nbsp; And I’ll leave it at that.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR: &amp;nbsp;Thank you.&amp;nbsp; Our next question will go to Neria with Israel Channel 13.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Hey, Kirby.&amp;nbsp; Thank you so much for doing that.&amp;nbsp; During Netanyahu’s speech/press conference last night, he said he told Sinwar forget about the Philadelphi Corridor.&amp;nbsp; I heard some officials saying that this could be the end for a possibility for a hostages deal.&amp;nbsp; So where do you get your optimism from?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And do you think that it was (inaudible) for the Prime Minister to say that?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And another question.&amp;nbsp; I do hear that the American hostages’ families are asking the U.S. administration to try and release their hostages in case Israel doesn’t want a hostages deal.&amp;nbsp; Can you tell us where does this stand?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; I won’t speculate about anything, not even the deal that we’re working on, at this point.&amp;nbsp; We still believe that that is the best way to get all the hostages back with their families, is to get this deal in place.&amp;nbsp; And as I said earlier, we believe we’re close enough and that the gaps are narrow enough to achieve that outcome.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;It’s not optimism, it’s pragmatism.&amp;nbsp; And it’s based on just looking at where we are, how far we’ve been able to come, and an essential belief that, practically speaking, these gaps can be narrowed.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;But, look, I can’t, nor would I ever, guarantee to you all that — a certain outcome.&amp;nbsp; We just believe that it is an outcome that’s possible.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; But is the U.S. working on such an option of releasing the American hostages?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; We are working on a proposal that would release all the hostages, including the American hostages, and that is the proposal that we’ve been talking about in the region last week, and it was the same proposal that the President met with his team over the weekend to discuss.&amp;nbsp; That is what we’re working on.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Thank you so much, Kirby.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; Yep.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR:&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp; Our next question will go to Jacob with the Times of Israel.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Hi.&amp;nbsp; Thanks for doing this.&amp;nbsp; To just follow up on a previous question: You said that the offer that Israel agreed to includes a withdrawal of IDF forces from heavily populated areas, including those areas along the Philadelphi Corridor.&amp;nbsp; Does that mean that in areas that aren’t heavily populated along the corridor, the U.S. supports or is okay with Israel staying there?&amp;nbsp; That’s one question.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Next, just being — you said you’re not using the term “final” to talk about the bridging proposal, but Brett had a briefing with us — it was on background — but he said several times that they’re calling it a final bridging proposal.&amp;nbsp; So is the White House now walking back from that terminology?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And then, you were asked about, lastly, reports that the U.S. could walk away from the talks.&amp;nbsp; I know in the past you’ve said “we’ll never walk away,” but that wasn’t your response this time.&amp;nbsp; So I just wanted to see if you’re — if there’s anything we should be learning from that, how you respond to that question.&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; What I’m hoping you can take away from this discussion today is how seriously we’re continuing to try to achieve a successful outcome here.&amp;nbsp; That’s what I want you to take away from it.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;On the Philadelphi Corridor, I think I could point you to what the Israelis have said publicly about their belief in the need to have some security along that corridor.&amp;nbsp; The proposal says that they have to remove themselves to the east from densely populated areas.&amp;nbsp; And that core, essential element of the proposal has not changed.&amp;nbsp; But the Israelis have said publicly that they believe that even in so doing, that they would need some security along that corridor, and I’d point you to what they’re saying about it.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; And on the terminology about “final” and “not final” bridging proposal?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; I’ve already answered — I’ve answered the question.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Okay, thank you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR:&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp; Our next question will go to Nathan with KAN.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Hey, thanks.&amp;nbsp; I’d like to know if the President has any plans of speaking to Netanyahu directly to clarify the issue of Philadelphi in the agreement.&amp;nbsp; He said yesterday that that will happen eventually.&amp;nbsp; But if this is such an urgent issue, can we expect any kind of direct contact between them immediately?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And also, is the U.S. in any kind of contact with the Israeli opposition and with the protest movement in Israel?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; I don’t have anything on the schedule in terms of another call with the Prime Minister, but I think you can safely assume that there will be additional conversations between these two leaders.&amp;nbsp; And when that happens, we will do what we do every time, which is let you know it’s happening and give you a readout when it’s happened.&amp;nbsp; I just don’t have anything to speak to at this time.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And we are not involving ourselves, nor would we, in Israeli domestic issues.&amp;nbsp; So I’d leave it at that.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR:&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp; Our next question will go to Nadia.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Sam.&amp;nbsp; John, the President said on seven different occasions that we are very close to conclude this deal, we’re closer than ever, we’re closer than three days ago.&amp;nbsp; I’m just wondering how — what is your understanding of what went wrong?&amp;nbsp; And why do you believe that a deal could be achieved, considering that both Sinwar and Netanyahu are not willing to compromise on fundamental issues?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And my second question is: Some of the families, the hostage families, are actually blaming the administration.&amp;nbsp; They’re saying that you did not exert enough pressure on Netanyahu, you didn’t use any leverage to make sure that the deal could be concluded a long time ago, and that could have spared the killing of the six hostages, despite the fact that Hamas executed them, but there could have been a way to spare their life.&amp;nbsp; How do you respond to this?&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; We were looking for that way as hard as humanly possible.&amp;nbsp; And we certainly understand the grief, the sorrow, the anger that they feel, because we feel it too.&amp;nbsp; But that doesn’t take away the incredible efforts that we expended to try to get this deal finished, and it certainly doesn’t diminish the efforts going forward, which will remain consistent, steadfast, and aggressive, to try to get this deal in place.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And when we said at the time, and I’ve said it many times myself, that we’re as close as we’ve ever been, that the gaps are narrow, those were accurate statements.&amp;nbsp; They were — they were true.&amp;nbsp; But we also never said it was going to be easy.&amp;nbsp; You can be that close.&amp;nbsp; And as I’ve said before, when you get to that close, when you get to that level of detail, that’s when the horse trading gets incredibly difficult.&amp;nbsp; That’s when the task of negotiators really intensifies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;And we’re still, we believe, in that space right now, where we have gaps that can be narrowed, but there’s no guarantee that they will be.&amp;nbsp; We just have to keep working as hard as we have been, and we will.&amp;nbsp; There’s not going to be any slackening of effort from the United States to try to see if we can’t hammer this out.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; And how do you respond to the fact that no leverage was used against Netanyahu?&amp;nbsp; Could you have used any pressure, publicly or publicly, to change his position?&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MR. KIRBY:&amp;nbsp; We’ve been working with Israel and Qatar and Egypt — the latter two, of course, have direct communications with Hamas — to do everything we can to find language that works for both sides to bring this deal to a close.&amp;nbsp; And that work was not completely — it was not completely fruitless.&amp;nbsp; We were able to narrow the gaps and get close.&amp;nbsp; But obviously, nothing is negotiated until everything is negotiated, and we haven’t concluded.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;So it’s not like — it’s not like we haven’t worked hard to move both sides closer to a deal.&amp;nbsp; And as I said, it doesn’t diminish the fact that we’re going to continue to work hard for that outcome.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;MODERATOR:&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&amp;nbsp; And that is, unfortunately, all the time we have today.&amp;nbsp; As always, if we weren’t able to get to you, please email the NSC Press distro and we’ll try to get back to you as soon as we can.&amp;nbsp; Thanks, everyone.&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 12:57 P.M. EDT&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2024/09/03/on-the-record-press-gaggle-by-white-house-national-security-communications-advisor-john-kirby-25/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/press-briefings/2024/09/03/on-the-record-press-gaggle-by-white-house-national-security-communications-advisor-john-kirby-25/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 21:40:32 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remarks by President Biden at the Investing in America Content Series Kickoff Event</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="container"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;South Court Auditorium&lt;br&gt;Eisenhower Executive Office Building&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;2:26 P.M. EDT&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MR. BENJAMIN: &amp;nbsp;Thank you all so much for being here. &amp;nbsp;We’re so delighted to speak to you today and to hear your stories.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s my pleasure to start the first of what will be many conversations just like this led by our president. &amp;nbsp;It’s also my honor today to have the opportunity to introduce President Biden to you. &amp;nbsp;He’s put investing in America at the forefront of his administration since day one. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, with that, I’d like to turn it over to our president, Joe Biden.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Well, thank you, Mayor, for that introduction. &amp;nbsp;And a special thanks to all of you for joining us. &amp;nbsp;Mayor Woodfin, Chairwoman Flores, Cecilia, as well as Jackie, it’s good to have you all. &amp;nbsp;You’ve all been incredible partners in the progress we’ve made together, which, quite frankly, is why we’re meeting today. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Four years ago when I came to office, the pandemic was raging and our economy was reeling. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Four years later, we still have more to do, but we had one of the most extraordinary periods of progress ever in the history of this country. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;COVID no longer controls our lives. &amp;nbsp;We’ve gone from economic crisis to the strongest economy in the world, literally: a record 16 million new jobs; record small-business growth; record stock market; record high 401(k)s; wages are up; inflation is down — way down and continuing to come down; and the smallest racial wealth gap in 20 years. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I signed historic laws modernizing our infrastructure; bringing new chip factories back to the United States — we invented those chips; lowering prescription drug prices and lowering them significantly; fighting the climate crisis and gun violence; and so much more. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the bottom line is thousands of cities and towns all across America are seeing the great American comeback story — whether they’re in red states or blue — all part of what we’re calling an Invest[ing] in America agenda. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s about seeking my commitment — speaking to the commitment I made as president to be president for all Americans, whether you voted for me or not, whether you’re in a red state or a blue state. &amp;nbsp;And it’s what being highlighted — we’re doing that today to highlight and show we’re just ge- — we’re just getting started. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the weeks ahead, I’ll talk with Americans all across the country about the progress we’re seeing in their communities: roads and bridges being built, lead pipes being removed from homes and schools, seniors saving significant money on prescription drug prices. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And through the Investing in America agenda, we planted the seeds for a better future, and now those seeds are finally beginning to sprout. &amp;nbsp;As a result, we’re on the cusp of incredible progress and prosperity for the decade to come. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That’s why we’re going to talk — what we’re going to talk about today: the stories about people whose lives are better and the future that we can be proud of. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’re proving once again what I’ve always believed: We’re the only nation in the world that’s come out of every crisis we’ve faced stronger than when we entered that crisis. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We just have to remember who we are. &amp;nbsp;We’re the United States of America, and nothing is beyond our capacity when we do it together. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, I’m going stop there, and I’m going to turn it over to Mayor Benjamin — who I just saw recently, by the way — to get the conversation going.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, by the way, Mr. Mayor, congratulations on that beautiful young child of yours. &amp;nbsp;That’s really — you — you’re — you’re a lucky man. &amp;nbsp;You tell me, she’s — is she already a supporter?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MAYOR WOODFIN: &amp;nbsp;Yes, she’s a supporter, sir. &amp;nbsp;Thank you, Mr. President. &amp;nbsp;(Laughter.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Well, God love you. &amp;nbsp;And — but really, God love your wife. &amp;nbsp;(Laughter.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MAYOR WOODFIN: &amp;nbsp;Yes, sir.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Any rate, fire away.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MR. BENJAMIN: &amp;nbsp;Go ahead, Randall. &amp;nbsp;Mayor Woodfin, go ahead and why don’t you share with us your Birmingham story.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MAYOR WOODFIN: &amp;nbsp;Well, listen, first let — would say we’re very, very thankful to you, Mr. President, and th- — and your entire administration, which has allowed us as a city and a government to truly focus on putting people first.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You know, over the last four years, as you stated, there has been an upswing. &amp;nbsp;For us, wages, income, and employment have been on the rise in Birmingham. &amp;nbsp;The average income has increased by more than $10,000, and we’ve exceeded pre-pandemic employment by over 17,000 jobs. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, Birmingham is seeing job creation. &amp;nbsp;We’re seeing growth in innovative industries and opportunity. &amp;nbsp;And I can say, without a doubt, that that is directly related to the Biden administration and your investments and support.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’re also tracking along national trends as it relates to small-business growth and expansion. &amp;nbsp;We even created an Office of Business Diversity and Opportunity to be intentionally focused on minority- and women-owned businesses.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And so, again, thank you to your administration. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our ARPA investment has stood up a COVID-relief forgivable loan program, where literally 9 out of every 10 recipients was either a Black- or woman-owned business. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And so, again, driving what your administration has allowed us to comp- — accomplish, designating — city of Birmingham being allowed to be designated as a tech hub has strengthened our recruitment efforts related to enhancing our innovation economy.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are a couple other notes I want to make. &amp;nbsp;One is that as part of your administration’s Good Jobs Challenge, we are training and placing up to 1,000 residents in health care careers.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, as the state of Alabama is the epicenter of the automotive industry, we’re seeing a boost because of your Inflation Reduction Act. &amp;nbsp;And because of those same investments in electric and batteries, in 2023, Alabama became the number one exporter of motor vehicles in the U.S., which we shipped more than 11 billion in automoti- — automotobiles [automobiles].&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These investments, Mr. President, helped us train workers right here in the city limits of Birmingham for more advanced manufacturing jobs. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, it doesn’t matter — through small businesses, clean energy, advanced manufacturing, and health care, our residents see more and more that they don’t have to leave their hometown, their city limits to get a good job, because they can get one right here.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And for us, in closing, that really means that the people of Birmingham are excited — excited for a brighter future; excited to see themselves in it, their families; and, for us, a great city. &amp;nbsp;So, we truly thank you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Well, Mayor, tell me, you know, up in North Birmingham, which is, I think, primarily a minority community, what are you doing up there to revitalize things?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MAYOR WOODFIN: &amp;nbsp;So, North Birmingham, first of all, it’s — it’s kind of personal to me. &amp;nbsp;I actually spent my first 11 years of life living in North Birmingham and went to North Birmingham Elementary. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But this area has been historically disadvantaged. &amp;nbsp;It is 100 percent minority — Black. &amp;nbsp;We’re talking about low — low employment, as well as fewer resources for its residents. &amp;nbsp;And so, we are so excited to receive a $20 million grant as part of the Distressed Area Recompete Pilot Program for this area. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And so, in this North Birmingham footprint, it is going to allow us to catalyze economic growth. &amp;nbsp;We call it Reinvest Birmingham. &amp;nbsp;This initiative — a little bit more detail — will allow us to rebuild something that’s so important to all communities, our North Birmingham Library. &amp;nbsp;And at this actual place, it affords us to create opportunity for learning and careers, as well as seeing a new workforce training site connected to this library for invest- — investments in entrepreneurship. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And my favorite part, because it’s part of the national conversation, it is a childcare facility. &amp;nbsp;Look —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;All right.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MAYOR WOODFIN: &amp;nbsp;So, that’s it, Mr. President. &amp;nbsp;It’s a — it’s a game changer for us. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MR. BENJAMIN: &amp;nbsp;Fantastic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Well, I tell you what, I can see Frederick Douglass’ book behind you. &amp;nbsp;He’s — he’s proud of you right now and your library.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, look —&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MAYOR WOODFIN: &amp;nbsp;Yes, sir.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Boss.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MR. BENJAMIN: &amp;nbsp;Sure. &amp;nbsp;So, tha- — thank you so much, Mayor Woodfin, for your leadership. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Now I have the chance to call on Ms. Jackie Trapp from Muskego, Wisconsin, to share her story with the president.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. TRAPP: &amp;nbsp;Thank you, Mr. Mayor and Mr. President. &amp;nbsp;I’m Jackie Trapp, a former social studies teacher turned family caregiver. &amp;nbsp;And in 2015, I was diagnosed with an incurable cancer, multiple myeloma. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Both the cancer and the chemotherapy caused blood clots, heart attacks, and strokes, so I’ll likely be on the critical blood thinner Xarelto for the rest of my life. &amp;nbsp;The new negotiated price of Xarelto, because of the Inflation Reduction Act, is a tremendous win for countless patients like me who rely on this previously cost-prohibitive medication to live.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Prior to the Inflation Reduction Act, my out-of-pocket drug costs ranged from $15- to over $21,000 a year every year for nine years. &amp;nbsp;My energy to fight my cancer was diverted to finding ways to fund my prescriptions. &amp;nbsp;It became my latest occupation, really.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MR. BENJAMIN: &amp;nbsp;Wow.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;(Coughs.) &amp;nbsp;Excuse me. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. TRAPP: &amp;nbsp;But on New Year’s Day, when everybody was ringing in the New Year, I actually celebrated my first fill of prescriptions, knowing that the $3,300 I paid was going to be my total for the year. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 2025, that cap drops to $2,000, and I won’t have to come up with tens of thousands of dollars every year anymore for my medication.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Before the Inflation Reduction Act, my husband and I used our savings; I navigated grants, took out home loans; we sold vehicles; and we sold furnishings and cut out all but the essentials just to meet my co-pays. &amp;nbsp;Ordinary things like dinner out, catching a movie, or exchanging gifts had pretty much ceased, and I thought no one would ever take on Big Pharma as they held patients like me hostage with monopolies over my essential drugs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, I cannot overstate my gratitude for this law, especially to you, President Biden. &amp;nbsp;Thank you so, so much for looking out for patients like me.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;I have one important question. &amp;nbsp;What’s your dog’s name?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. TRAPP: &amp;nbsp;(Laughs.) &amp;nbsp;My dog is Jake.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Jake. &amp;nbsp;(Laughs.) &amp;nbsp;Well, I tell you what —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. TRAPP: &amp;nbsp;Jake, the dog.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Look, you know, I want people to understand that I’ve been having this run-in with Big Pharma for a long time. &amp;nbsp;We finally beat them. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And the Xarelto you’re taking — were — taking, it used to cost $517. &amp;nbsp;It’s now $197 for people on Medicare. &amp;nbsp;And the idea that you were paying as much — I mean, the Inflation Reduction Act, $2,000 out-of-pocket annual cap for Medicare prescription drugs. &amp;nbsp;And it’s — it’s got to be a life-changer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You know, the mental impact of having to figure, “If I don’t take these drugs, my life is literally at stake,” and having to figure out, “How in God’s name — how in God’s name can we get the money to do it?”&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I’m so proud of you. &amp;nbsp;Presumptuous of me to say that; I’ve never met you personally. &amp;nbsp;But I really am. &amp;nbsp;I’m proud as hell of you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. TRAPP: &amp;nbsp;Thank you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;You’re just a real fighter, and you look great. &amp;nbsp;I hope it’s — I hope you feel as good as you look.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. TRAPP: &amp;nbsp;Well, I am so grateful. &amp;nbsp;I can’t even overstate that. &amp;nbsp;Really, thank you. &amp;nbsp;This opportunity to thank you means quite a bit to me.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Well, all of you got to come to the White — I’m not going to be in the White House much longer, but you got to come and see me. &amp;nbsp;I want to see you all.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. TRAPP: &amp;nbsp;(Inaudible.) &amp;nbsp;(Laughs.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;All right?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, Mr. Mayor.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MR. BENJAMIN: &amp;nbsp;Well, we’ll get — we’ll figure that out, boss. &amp;nbsp;We’ll figure that out.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. TRAPP: &amp;nbsp;(Laughs.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MR. BENJAMIN: &amp;nbsp;Thank you so much for your courage, Ms. Trapp, and — and keep on fighting.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. TRAPP: &amp;nbsp;Thank you. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MR. BENJAMIN: &amp;nbsp;Now I have the honor of — of calling on Chairwoman Amel- — Amelia Flores to share her story. &amp;nbsp;Madam Chair.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. FLORES: &amp;nbsp;Kwichkamaduum, Mr. President. &amp;nbsp;It’s an honor to be here with you today. &amp;nbsp;My name is Amelia Flores, and I am the chairwoman of the Colorado River Indian Tribes, also known as CRIT. &amp;nbsp;And I’m very proud to be the first woman elected to lead our Tribe. &amp;nbsp;We broke the glass ceiling on December 5th, 2020. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And I’ve seen firsthand how poor infrastructure — be it water, schools, broadband, our roads — has impacted my Tribe. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For an example, during my first few months on the job, our Tribal utility director came to me with some bad news: We did — we needed a new well. &amp;nbsp;And I knew our Tribal budget was already taxed to the breaking point, and there was no way we could have pulled this off until you passed the ARPA and Bipartisan Infrastructure Law.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;ARPA helped us fix the broken well, and BIL provided more than $7 million to build new wells and improve our distribution system.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Phase one is completed. &amp;nbsp;The well is once again serving 1,850 homes and businesses. &amp;nbsp;And when we complete phase two, the new well and distribution system will be able to deliver safe and reliable water to more than 1,000 additional homes and businesses in our community.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This project will allow us to address the housing shortage on our reservation. &amp;nbsp;That means more families can live together on our Tribal land. &amp;nbsp;It helps our businesses and our economy grow. &amp;nbsp;Together, that strengthens our culture and, most importantly, our sovereignty. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The well and water treatment plant will have a long-term impact in our community, and I am grateful for your leadership in making that all happen, Mr. President.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Well, I’m grateful to you. &amp;nbsp;And, by the way, I learned a long time ago from a friend of mine from Hawaii — a senior senator when I got elected as a tw- — 30-year-old kid to the Senate. &amp;nbsp;He said, “Joe, it’s Indian Nations. &amp;nbsp;Indian Nations.” &amp;nbsp;And that’s exactly how you’re handling it. &amp;nbsp;That’s how it’s treated. &amp;nbsp;And the sovereignty is real. &amp;nbsp;And you need the help. &amp;nbsp;You need the help. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And — and let me ask you a question, Chairwoman.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. FLORES: &amp;nbsp;Sure.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;How are these investments helping your community see a brighter c- — future for themselves and their families? &amp;nbsp;Is there anything just beyond the water? &amp;nbsp;Is — is it the mere fact that the water is there; that’s why everybody’s excited? &amp;nbsp;Or it’s that you’re able to begin to fashion your own destiny a little bit?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. FLORES: &amp;nbsp;Well, thank you, Mr. President, for that question. &amp;nbsp;And certainly, with the monies that have come from ARPA and — and the bipartisan law, it allows for more people to return back to the reservation, because many of our Tribal members leave the reservation to find work. &amp;nbsp;And when they leave, they oftentime- — oftentimes take their families with them. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And then eventually, 20, 30 years after, they want to come back home, and that’s hard because we don’t have the housing or the infrastructure for them to come back. &amp;nbsp;And we haven’t been able to do that for them. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, with this project, with the new wells and upcoming water treatment system, we will have cleaner and safer water. &amp;nbsp;We now have the infrastructure we need to build for housing for our people, and we can build up our community. &amp;nbsp;We’ll have more families here, and that really changes things up for us and gives us hope. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, yes, we’re the Tribes with the water. &amp;nbsp;We have senior water rights on the Lower Colorado River Basin. &amp;nbsp;And we have the largest water right.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;I know you do, and — and it’s about time everybody recognized it. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And we just had a photograph up on the other board here while you were talking about how beautiful the countryside is. &amp;nbsp;It’s a magnificent area. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, thank you, and you’re doing a great job. &amp;nbsp;Thank you very much. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. FLORES: &amp;nbsp;Thank you. &amp;nbsp;Thank you, and God bless you. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENET: &amp;nbsp;Thank you. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MR. BENJAMIN: &amp;nbsp;Thank you. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, now it’s our honor, we have Ms. Cecilia Moy Yep from Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, here to share her story. &amp;nbsp;Please, Ms. Moy Yep. &amp;nbsp;Please.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. YEP: &amp;nbsp;Thank you. &amp;nbsp;My name is Cecilia Moy Yep. &amp;nbsp;In 1966, I was a widow with three small children living in Chinatown, Philadelphia. &amp;nbsp;I was at a public meeting when I found out that the church and school my children went to was going to be demolished for a federal highway program. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The church was the heart and lifeblood of the community, so I got involved. &amp;nbsp;I formed a grassroots organization to fight against the highway. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We organized. &amp;nbsp;We picketed. &amp;nbsp;We protested. &amp;nbsp;But we did have some success because we were successful in protecting the school and the church from being demolished. &amp;nbsp;But despite our efforts, the Vine Street Expressway was still built through the heart of Chinatown. &amp;nbsp;And even over the years, many of my neighbors and I were forced out of our houses because of other transportation projects. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Vine Street Expressway created a physical divide that made Chinatown less safe. &amp;nbsp;It made our air quality worse. &amp;nbsp;The construction displaced so many people from our community. &amp;nbsp;But from the very beginning, we tried to get the highway capped to improve safety and to reconnect Chinatown, but there was never funding to make it happen. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But now, after 50 years of organizing, thanks to you and your administration for — for their investment in the Chinatown Stitch project, this dream will finally become a reality. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our community has been asking for this for decades, and it would never have happened without your funding. &amp;nbsp;Thank you so much for delivering, Mr. President, for our community.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Cecilia, I know your community pretty well. &amp;nbsp;I live down the road in Delaware. &amp;nbsp;And I-95 went through my community, and — and it — it d- — not where I live, but in — in West — the western part of the city. &amp;nbsp;And it divided entire communities. &amp;nbsp;It’s four lanes across, and we’ve been fighting for a long time. &amp;nbsp;We finally got commitments — we got the money. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For example, you’re going to get — you’re going to share a now $159 million — $159 million from the Inflation Reduction Act. &amp;nbsp;And the — the China[town] Stitch project is going to reconnect Philadelphia Chinatown, which was divided in construction back in the ‘60s with the Vine — the Vine Street Expressway. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. YEP: &amp;nbsp;Yeah.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;That project will cover 2.5 blocks of expressway with public green space, achieving the goal you’ve been fighting for for nearly 60 years. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I know you’re only 62 years old, but you’ve been fighting a long time. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. YEP: &amp;nbsp;I wish. &amp;nbsp;I wish. &amp;nbsp;(Laughter.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;The Department of Transportation experts are — signed a grant agreement in January. &amp;nbsp;The project is going to take a while to get done, but it will — we expect it to begin full bor- — full-blown in 2028 and be completed by — in early ‘31. &amp;nbsp;So, it’s going to take a little time, but it’s going to be complete. &amp;nbsp;It’s going to be done. &amp;nbsp;The money is there and —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. YEP: &amp;nbsp;I hope I’m still alive to see it. &amp;nbsp;(Laughter.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;You’ll be alive. &amp;nbsp;You’ll be — God love you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. YEP: &amp;nbsp;But it’s something the — yeah, it’s something the community has wanted for a long, long time. &amp;nbsp;And this will give our community, families, and children the peace of mind knowing that people can be safe going to school and to work. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It means a lot to know that the federal government listened to us and is helping us to build a brighter future for families right here in Chinatown. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Well, all —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. YEP: &amp;nbsp;Thank you, Mr. President.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;All over the country, we’re doing this.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, by the way, there’s a photograph of you with a shovel in your hand up on the board here and a hard hat on, celebrating the turn of the spade to this getting going. &amp;nbsp;And what I don’t want you to do: I don’t — I don’t want you working beyond 5 o’clock at night, though. &amp;nbsp;Okay? &amp;nbsp;(Laughter.) &amp;nbsp;You got to promise me you’ll be home. &amp;nbsp;(Laughs.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. YEP: &amp;nbsp;That’s hard, because when you’re doing community work, it’s always at night. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;I — that’s true. &amp;nbsp;Well, God love you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. YEP: &amp;nbsp;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Cecilia, I’m so — so, so proud of you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. YEP: &amp;nbsp;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;I really am so proud of you. &amp;nbsp;Presumptuous of me to say that, but I am.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, thank you all very much. &amp;nbsp;This just — all the families deserve to have things that we shared today, not just — not just the four and their community: peace of mind, having clean and safe water, affordable medicine to stay healthy, safe roads and bridges to connect communities rather than divide them, and so much more. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;All Americans deserve a future worthy of their dreams. &amp;nbsp;And that future, we’re building today. &amp;nbsp;And we’re doing it, and we’re able to afford to do it. &amp;nbsp;Turning setbacks into comebacks, that’s what America does.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And I want to thank you for what you’re doing. &amp;nbsp;And I’m excited — excited about sharing your investment stories with all of America, seeing more of them in the weeks and months ahead to let people know we can do anything in America. &amp;nbsp;We really can. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And we can afford to do it. &amp;nbsp;Instead of giving billion-dollar tax — trillion-dollar tax cuts to the super-wealthy, let them start paying their fair share. &amp;nbsp;Let them make sure we get — make —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Look, all people want in America is just a shot, just a chance, just to be treated fairly and equally. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And that’s what you all are doing. &amp;nbsp;That’s what you’re all a part of. &amp;nbsp;And I hope I get to see you all in person one of these days. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, thank you, thank you, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;God bless you all. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;MS. YEP: &amp;nbsp;Thank you, Mr. President.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;Thank you. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;May God protect our troops.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Any progress on the ceasefire deal today?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;Mr. President, what more should Netanyahu be doing, sir?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(Cross-talk.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT: &amp;nbsp;The answer to all your questions is whatever you want to hear.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp; 2:49 P.M. EDT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/09/03/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-investing-in-america-content-series-kickoff-event/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/09/03/remarks-by-president-biden-at-the-investing-in-america-content-series-kickoff-event/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 19:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remarks by Vice President Harris at a Campaign Event | Detroit, MI</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="container"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;Northwestern High School&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;Detroit, Michigan&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;1:19 P.M. EDT&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Hi, everyone.&amp;nbsp; Good afternoon, Detroit.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Oh, it’s good to be in the house of labor.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Can we hear it for Tyrese?&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Tyrese, I want to thank you for your extraordinary leadership and all of your words and the heart and soul that you put into your work, like I know all the members of LIUNA and everyone here does every day, because we love our country and we know what is at stake.&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Tyrese.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, it is so good to be with so many incredible leaders and elected officials who are here.&amp;nbsp; Governor Whitmer was here earlier — (applause); Senator Stabenow; your next United States senator, Representative Elissa Slotkin.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;And I always want to thank Representatives Dingell — where is she?&amp;nbsp; There she — there she is.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Stevens, Thanedar, all of you for the work that you do every day.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;And to all the labor leaders who are here, I thank you all for your extraordinary work.&amp;nbsp; Don’t we love Labor Day?&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; We love Labor Day.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;It’s always been that way, right?&amp;nbsp; The way we celebrate Labor Day is we know that hard work is good work.&amp;nbsp; We know that when we organize, when we bring everyone together, it’s a joyful moment where we are committed to doing the hard work of lifting up America’s families.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And I want to thank everyone here for that work and the way you do it every day, including General President Booker of the Laborers’ — (applause); President Fain of UAW — (applause); President Pringle of NEA — (applause); President Slevin of the Utility Workers — (applause); and President Weingarten of the AFT.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And thank you to all of the union members who are here this afternoon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, on Labor Day and every day, we celebrate the dignity of work — the dignity of work.&amp;nbsp; We celebrate unions, because unions helped build America and unions helped build America’s middle class.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It is true across our nation, and it is true here in Detroit.&amp;nbsp; Nearly 140 years ago, in this very city, 10,000 people marched in one of our nation’s first Labor Day parades.&amp;nbsp; Many held signs that read “Divided, we can beg.&amp;nbsp; United, we can demand.”&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For generations, in Detroit and across our nation, the brothers and sisters of labor have stood together to righteously demand fair pay, better benefits, and safe working conditions.&amp;nbsp; And let me say, every person in our nation has benefited from that work.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Everywhere I go, I tell people: Look, you may not be a union member.&amp;nbsp; You better thank a union member — (applause) — for the five-day workweek.&amp;nbsp; You better thank a union member for sick leave.&amp;nbsp; You better thank a union member for paid leave.&amp;nbsp; You better thank a union member for vacation time.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because what we know is when union wages go up, everybody’s wages go up.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; When union workplaces are safer, every workplace is safer.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; When unions are strong, America is strong.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We know what we’re talking about.&amp;nbsp; The labor movement has always understood the power of the collective and the power of unity — the power of unity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;And while we are fighting so much nonsense that is about trying to divide our country, trying to pull us apart, look to what the history and the present of labor tells us about the power of the collective and unity — the spirit of that work, as much as the product of that work.&amp;nbsp; It’s very telling and gives us really good lessons about what creates strength.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, you know, many of you know, my parents met while they were active in the Civil Rights Movement.&amp;nbsp; So, when I was young, my parents — because I see some young leaders here today — when I was young, my parents would take me to the meetings — I see our young leaders — (applause) — and — and take me to the marches.&amp;nbsp; I was in a stroller.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And from a very young age, I learned that when people stand together, when we join voices, knowing that the vast majority of us have so much more in common than what separates us — when we join those voices, we can drive extraordinary change, which is why I believe in my heart and soul no one should ever be made to fight alone.&amp;nbsp; We are all in this together.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; We are all in this together.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But I’ll tell you, I think that there has been a certain backward-thinking approach over the last several years, which is to suggest — some folks, them folks — to suggest that the measure of the strength of a leader is based on who you beat down instead of what we know: The true measure of the strength of a leader is based on who you lift up — who you lift up.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; That’s the measure of the strength of a leader.&amp;nbsp; Let’s stop with the nonsense.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And in this election, we all here know there are two very different visions for our nation.&amp;nbsp; Ours, focused on the future; the other, focused —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt; AUDIENCE MEMBER:&amp;nbsp; (Inaudible.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-left"&gt;&amp;nbsp;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; (Laughs.)&amp;nbsp; Let’s just get through the next 64 days.&amp;nbsp; How about — (laughs).&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;And ours — yes, my dear brother — is focused on the future, and theirs is focused on the past.&amp;nbsp; And we fight for the future.&amp;nbsp; We fight for a future where all people receive dignity and respect and opportunity for — not just for some but for all.&amp;nbsp; That’s what we are fighting for.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And so, we are 64 days out from the election day.&amp;nbsp; And in Michigan, mail-in absentee voting starts in 24 days — (applause) — 24 days.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, this election — this election and our fight is a fight for the promise of America, a promise —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE MEMBER:&amp;nbsp; We love you, Kamala!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; I love you back.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;And ours is a fight for the promise — the promise of America — a promise of freedom, of opportunity, and justice not just for some but for all.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But what we know is, as we fight to move our nation forward, Donald Trump intends to pull us back to the past.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; But we’re not going back.&amp;nbsp; We are not going back.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; So — and let’s — and — and we know — we know what that would look like, right?&amp;nbsp; So, intends to pull us back, including back to a time before workers had the freedom to organize.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As president, we will always remember Donald Trump blocked overtime benefits for millions of workers —&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; — Tyrese talked a bit about this — and opposed efforts to raise the minimum wage.&amp;nbsp; He appointed union busters to the National Labor Relations Board.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; And he supported so-called right-to-work laws.&amp;nbsp; And if —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Trump is a scab!&amp;nbsp; Trump is a scab!&amp;nbsp; Trump is a scab!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Well, — well, here’s the thing.&amp;nbsp; Here’s the thing.&amp;nbsp; We have a choice here, right?&amp;nbsp; And — and we’re not going back, because we also know that if Donald Trump were reelected, he intends to give tax cuts to billionaires and big corporations.&amp;nbsp; He intends to cut Social Security and Medicare.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; He wants to impose what in effect is a national sales tax on everyday products and basic necessities that will cost — and economists have said this — that will cost a typical American family almost $4,000 a year.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; He wants to repeal the Affordable Care Act —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo –&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; — and take us back to a time in our country which most of us remember, when insurance companies, you remember, had the power to deny people coverage based on a preexisting condition.&amp;nbsp; Remember that?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Deny people — children who had asthma, a survivor of breast cancer, a grandparent with diabetes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Look, America has tried those failed policies before.&amp;nbsp; And they are failed policies.&amp;nbsp; And we are not going back.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; We are not going back.&amp;nbsp; We are not going back.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; And instead — and instead, we fight for a future — a future where no person has to go broke just because they got sick.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And so, when I am president, we will continue to strengthen the Affordable Care Act.&amp;nbsp; We will bring down the cost of prescription drugs not only for some but for all Americans.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We — we fight for a future where every worker has the freedom to organize.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And so, when I am president, we will pass the PRO Act and end union busting once and for all.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And I’ll remind everybody, on all these bills, we got to elect a Congress who supports that — (applause) — to be able to actually get that work done.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We fight for a future where every person has the opportunity not just to get by but to get ahead.&amp;nbsp; And so, when I am president, we will continue to build what I call an “opportunity economy” so that every American has an opportunity to own a home, to start a business, to build intergenerational wealth for their family.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We fight for a future where every senior can retire with dignity.&amp;nbsp; And so, when I am president, we will continue to defend Social Security, Medicare, and pensions, just like we have done.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Kamala!&amp;nbsp; Kamala!&amp;nbsp; Kamala!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Sixty-four days — 64 days — the most important election of our lives and probably one of the most important in the life of our nation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And here’s what I’d say to all the brothers and sisters assembled: We know this is going to be a very tight race to the very end.&amp;nbsp; We know — we know —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE MEMBER:&amp;nbsp; (Inaudible.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; And I got your back.&amp;nbsp; But I’m telling you, we know how they play.&amp;nbsp; We know what they do.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;So, let’s not pay too much attention to the polls.&amp;nbsp; Let’s know, like labor always does: We are out here running like we are the underdog in this race, because we know what we are fighting for.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; We know what we stand for, and that’s why we know what we fight for.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And we got some hard work ahead of us.&amp;nbsp; But, again, we all like hard work, because hard work is good work.&amp;nbsp; And to do that hard work, I’m going to count on everyone here, all the leaders here, for your work, for your organizing, knocking on doors, and getting folks to the polls.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;Because, put bluntly, Michigan, y’all know how to win.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; You know how to win.&amp;nbsp; You know how to win.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;So, today, I ask: Detroit, Michigan, are you ready to have your voices heard?&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Do we believe in freedom?&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Do we believe in opportunity?&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Do we believe in the promise of America?&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; And are we ready to fight for it?&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; And when we fight —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; We win!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; — we win.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; God bless you.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;END&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 1:36 P.M. EDT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/09/02/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-a-campaign-event-detroit-mi/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/09/02/remarks-by-vice-president-harris-at-a-campaign-event-detroit-mi/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 02:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remarks by President Biden After Marine One Arrival</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="container"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;South Lawn&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;8:42 P.M. EDT&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Mr. President, do you have plans to speak to Netanyahu?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; I can’t see you or hear you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Hi.&amp;nbsp; Do you have any plans to speak to Prime Minister Netanyahu?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Eventually.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; This week?&amp;nbsp; Tomorrow?&amp;nbsp; (Inaudible)?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Eventually.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; On Ukraine —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; What — Mr. President —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Mr. President, on Ukraine.&amp;nbsp; Have you seen Ukraine’s request to lift restrictions on American weapons so they can strike back on Russian bases?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; I’ve made it clear what we propo- — what we support and don’t support.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Mr. President, how was it to be back on the campaign trail today?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; It feels good.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Feels good?&amp;nbsp; How do you feel about Pennsylvania?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Except I’m not able to go out in the crowds anymore.&amp;nbsp; They don’t — the Secret Service doesn’t let me.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; No?&amp;nbsp; Why not?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Well, because they said it’s too dangerous.&amp;nbsp; No one gets to go out.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (Inaudible.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; (Inaudible.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (Inaudible.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; (Laughs.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Q&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; How do you feel about Pennsylvania right now?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; I feel real good about Pennsylvania.&amp;nbsp; I think we’re going to win Pennsylvania.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;8:44 P.M. EDT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/09/02/remarks-by-president-biden-after-marine-one-arrival-25/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/09/02/remarks-by-president-biden-after-marine-one-arrival-25/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:42:00 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remarks by President Biden and Vice President Harris at a Campaign Event | Pittsburgh, PA</title>
      <description>&lt;div class="container"&gt;
&lt;div class="row"&gt;



&lt;p class="has-text-align-center"&gt;IBEW Local 5&lt;br&gt;Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;5:26 P.M. EDT&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Hello!&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Hello, hello, hello!&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Hello, Pittsburgh!&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Thank you, thank you, thank you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Folks, I’ve celebrated many Labor Days in Pittsburgh.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And it’s always good to be back with so many great friends, many of whom flew with me on Air Force One today — represent the unions that have been with me since the beginning of my career — they’re not that old, but they — they’re — (laughter) — since I was a 29-year-old kid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I want to thank Liz Shuler of the AFL-CIO — (applause) — and Kenny of the IBEW — (applause) — for that strong endorsement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By the way, we have an expression in Delaware.&amp;nbsp; The IBEW, when I ran for president, they’re the ones that “brung me to the dance” starting off.&amp;nbsp; Not a joke.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And Dave McCall and the Steelworkers.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Dave, in 1972 — Steelworkers were the first union to endorse a 29-year-old kid named Joe Biden who wasn’t old enough to be senator when he got elected.&amp;nbsp; It mattered.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A guy named Hughie Carcella was the district president, because we used to have one of the largest labor forces in Claymont, Delaware, and north — over 4,000 workers.&amp;nbsp; And it was — anyway, it all went lo- — it went south.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But Hughie — Hughie went to the national president, I. — I.W. Abel, and he said he wanted me — he wanted me to get ele- — endorsed.&amp;nbsp; Everybody thought it was crazy.&amp;nbsp; I literally wasn’t old enough to be sworn in the day I got elected.&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But guess what?&amp;nbsp; President Abel stuck with me.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And they got stuck with me for the rest of their — my career.&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eric Dean and the Iron Workers.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Tim Driscoll of Bricklayers.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; April Verrett and SEIU.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lee Saunders of AFSCME and a great friend.&amp;nbsp; Where are you, Lee?&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And Jimmy Williams and the Painters and Allied Trades.&amp;nbsp; And his dad.&amp;nbsp; His dad is a really good man.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And Mike Coleman and the Sheet Metal Workers.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We’ve also got some of the best elected officials in America.&amp;nbsp; Governor Josh Shapiro is doing an incredible job.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And the great Lieutenant Governor Austin Davis.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And one of America’s best — where is Ed Gainey?&amp;nbsp; Ed, you’re doing a hell of a job.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And Sara Innamorato.&amp;nbsp; County executive, I think, is the hardest job in American politics.&amp;nbsp; Everybody knows where you live, and they think you can solve all the problems.&amp;nbsp; You don’t have enough money.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But I tell you one thing, I’m the first president ever — I used to be a county official when I was 26 years old, and it always bothered me that the county — the sta- — the federal government would send money to the state to be distributed to the county.&amp;nbsp; What the hell is the state going to send to the county for?&amp;nbsp; All the state reps need the money.&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But guess what?&amp;nbsp; Under my administration, it goes straight to the county.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And one of my best friends — my name is Joe Biden; I’m from Scranton, Pennsylvania.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Bobby Casey has been a great friend.&amp;nbsp; His dad was a great friend as well.&amp;nbsp; And, by the way, we grew up three blocks from one another.&amp;nbsp; Three blocks.&amp;nbsp; And they still worry about us not showing up.&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And guess what?&amp;nbsp; I was on North Washington Avenue; he was on Adams.&amp;nbsp; Guess what?&amp;nbsp; They’ve renamed North Washington Avenue down where I lived “Biden Way.”&amp;nbsp; (Inaudible.)&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And, Bobby — Bob, we’ll make sure we get — you get reelected again.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And while he couldn’t be here, I want to thank his partner in the Senate, John Fetterman.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; If you’re in a foxhole, you want Fetterman in there with you.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; He couldn’t be here today, but guess what?&amp;nbsp; He sent the best part of the family, Gisele.&amp;nbsp; She’s here.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let me just say it means so much to be with a true friend — a true friend: the vice president and the next great president of the United States of America, Kamala Harris.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Look, folks, I come from two neighborhoods where it’s not hard to say the word “union.”&amp;nbsp; But you know what?&amp;nbsp; The fact of the matter is an awful lot of politicians have trouble saying “union.”&amp;nbsp; (Inaudible) working people.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Guess what?&amp;nbsp; I’m not one of them.&amp;nbsp; Neither is Kamala.&amp;nbsp; We know the simple truth.&amp;nbsp; Wall Street did not build America; the middle class built America, and unions built the middle class.&amp;nbsp; That’s a fact.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, by the way, that is a not a slogan.&amp;nbsp; That’s a fact.&amp;nbsp; I asked the Treasury Department to do a study, and it shows that when unions do well, all workers in America do better.&amp;nbsp; That’s a fact.&amp;nbsp; That’s a fact.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It’s the biggest reason why our economy is the strongest economy in the world today without question — because of unions.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You know, my dad, like many of his generation, going into World War II, wasn’t able to go to — to college.&amp;nbsp; My dad was a really well-read guy, and he was always engaged.&amp;nbsp; And he’d come home from work before he’d go back and close up his shop and — for dinner.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And the dinner was a place where we had discussions and, incidentally, ate.&amp;nbsp; You know, my dad taught me — my dad would say this all the time: “Remember, Joey, a job is” — and I give you my word to this — “a job is about a lot more than a paycheck.&amp;nbsp; It’s about your dignity.&amp;nbsp; It’s about community.&amp;nbsp; It’s about your place in the community.&amp;nbsp; And it’s about being able to look your kid in the eye and say, ‘Honey, it’s going to be okay,’ and mean it.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, that’s why — (applause) — that’s why Kamala and I are so proud — so proud of the greatest job creation record of any president in a single term in American history.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sixteen million new jobs so far.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Eight hundred thousand manufacturing jobs.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Eight years ago, how many times you hear about we can no longer be the manufacturing capital of the world?&amp;nbsp; Where the hell is that written?&amp;nbsp; We are the greatest manufacturing city — or county in the world — state in the world — (inaudible) the world.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And we’re going to remain that way.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And I’ll tell you something.&amp;nbsp; Kamala and I are damn proud that we protected the pensions of over 1 million workers and retirees.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Remember all those years of promising we were going to do something about it?&amp;nbsp; Well, damn it, we finally did it with the Butch Lewis Act.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Over 52,000 workers and retirees across Pennsylvania alone are benefitting from that.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Not only did we restore the full amount, we got them their back pay as well.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; We made them whole again.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And as I once said to Barack, “That’s a big deal.”&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&amp;nbsp; Yeah.&amp;nbsp; Long story.&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You just heard Liz and Kenny describe another big deal.&amp;nbsp; Union workers are rebuilding American infrastructure and building new factories here in America.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;They told me we couldn’t get anything done in infrastructure.&amp;nbsp; A trillion two hundred billion dollars we got done.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Remember Trump, for four years, promised every month “Infrastructure Week.”&amp;nbsp; For four years, he promised that.&amp;nbsp; He didn’t build a damn thing.&amp;nbsp; Nothing.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; I mean it.&amp;nbsp; Not — nothing.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, thanks to our infrastructure law, Pennsylvania, so far, has received $17 billion — $17 billion.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Over 2,000 projects, from clean water to affordable high-speed Internet for every Pennsylvanian to projects that include $858 million to expand the Montgomery Lock better — to accommodate bigger barges to get millions of tons of goods and shel- — on shelves faster and more reliable and create thousands of union jobs.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I was working on the Great Lakes, and I got a call from Bobby — from Senator Casey.&amp;nbsp; He’s been — no bigger champion than Casey for this.&amp;nbsp; You know what I call them?&amp;nbsp; I call them the “Casey Locks.”&amp;nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&amp;nbsp; Not Goldilocks.&amp;nbsp; The Casey Locks.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bobby is also a champion of Pennsylvania’s energy communities.&amp;nbsp; We passed what’s called the Casey Credit, available to 45 Pennsylvania counties where energy jobs such as coal — where coal mining and — had been before it disappeared, before we came to office.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Casey Credit provides major incentives for companies to build new battery factories, wind turbines, and more to create high-paying jobs in those coal and natural gas communities.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And on top of that, there’s over $4 billion that private companies have committed to invest in clean energy and advanced manufacturing here in Pennsylvania — $4 billion.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And guess what?&amp;nbsp; With your support, I signed an executive order to make sure large federal construction projects all use project labor agreements.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For folks at home who may be watching this on television know what project labor agreement is, it’s when contractors, subcontractors, and unions put in place before construction begins what the rules are — before it begins.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;These agreements make sure construction is top-notch, on time, on task, and, by the way, on budget.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There’s another big deal.&amp;nbsp; “Buy American” — that’s been the law since 1930.&amp;nbsp; I’ve got to admit, I’ve been around — I’m only 40, but I’ve been around a long time.&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&amp;nbsp; But I, quite frankly, until 10 years ago, wasn’t aware — you know, back in the ‘30s, when they were trying to make sure unions could organize and businesses couldn’t interfere, they put — a law was passed that said every penny the president gets from the Senate, the House, and Congress to spend on a project, he should hire an American worker and use an American product.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But past administrations — (applause) — seriously.&amp;nbsp; Past administrations, including my pres- — predecessor, failed to buy American.&amp;nbsp; They shipped jobs overseas where labor was cheaper and brought home the product that was more expensive.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But not anymore.&amp;nbsp; Federal projects build American roads, bridges, highways, and they’ll be made with American products by American workers.&amp;nbsp; That’s why — (applause) — that’s why we’re creating all these — I’m serious.&amp;nbsp; It’s simple and basic.&amp;nbsp; That’s why we’re creating so many good-paying jobs.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In fact, we’re requiring those kinds of projects to pay Davis-Bacon prevailing wages so they’re jobs you can raise a family on.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many of those jobs don’t require a college degree.&amp;nbsp; In fact, we expanded registered apprenticeships.&amp;nbsp; Remember all the hell I got for doing that — we got for doing that?&amp;nbsp; Well, guess what?&amp;nbsp; It resulted in hiring over 1 million apprentices since we came to office.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And lots of folks don’t realize getting an apprenticeship is like getting a college degree.&amp;nbsp; Why?&amp;nbsp; You have to train for four or five years to get that.&amp;nbsp; And some of the best workers in the world are why the — why we are where we are.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You know — (applause) — when you’re in Pittsburgh, you’re standing with steelworkers.&amp;nbsp; Let’s be clear.&amp;nbsp; I believe in American steel companies — American-owned-and-operated steel companies.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; A simple reason — it’s not hyperbole — American steelworkers are the best steelworkers in the world.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And I made it clear last time I was in Pittsburgh: United States Steel, an iconic American company for more than a century, is going to remain an American company.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I remember as a young senator why the N- — National Labor Relations Board was sometimes so anti-labor.&amp;nbsp; It was set up to help labor, to be pro-labor.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Well, guess what?&amp;nbsp; That’s why one of the most significant things we’ve done, Kamala and I, is appointing a National Labor Reser- — Board — Relations Board that actually believes in unions and believes in recognizing the right to organize.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; It’s a big deal.&amp;nbsp; It’s a big deal.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Remember — we have short memories.&amp;nbsp; I’m all for forgiveness.&amp;nbsp; I’m not for this: Trump appointed union busters on that board.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; No, that’s a fact.&amp;nbsp; But it’s real.&amp;nbsp; It affects people’s lives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Are we going to let that son of a gun do that again?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; No!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Folks, we’ve made a lot of progress, and Kamala and I are going to build on that progress, and she’s going to build on it.&amp;nbsp; I’ll be on the sidelines, but I’ll do everything I can to help.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But, look, I’m not joking when I say — this is not a joke.&amp;nbsp; When I said this when I was running in 2020, a lot of people didn’t believe me.&amp;nbsp; You did, but a lot didn’t believe me.&amp;nbsp; It’s all at risk because of Donald Trump, literally.&amp;nbsp; With a stroke of the pen, he can get rid of a lot of this.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And do you think this guy gives a damn about your pensions?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; No!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; No, I’m serious.&amp;nbsp; Do you think he lo- — loses even an instant of sleep over it?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; No!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Do you think he cares about all the work you do every day and how hard it is?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; No!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Do you think he cares about good-paying jobs for hardworking people who built this economy?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; No!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Hell — (laughter) — he regards picket lines — he’d rather cross one than walk one.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But I have no problem walking a picket line.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Never have.&amp;nbsp; Neither — nor does Kamala.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; We’ll always walk aside — alongside you.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Union workers built this country.&amp;nbsp; And, again, that’s not hyperbole.&amp;nbsp; That’s a fact.&amp;nbsp; These are — these are facts.&amp;nbsp; These are not campaign slogans.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let me close with this.&amp;nbsp; Five years ago, I began my campaign for president right here in Pittsburgh.&amp;nbsp; I said one of the reasons I was running was to rebuild the backbone and spine of America — the middle class and working-class folks.&amp;nbsp; Not a joke.&amp;nbsp; Think about it.&amp;nbsp; Think about it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Well, five years later, we’ve done just that.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I’m back in Pittsburgh on Labor Day again with a simple message as we look at this election.&amp;nbsp; I &lt;s&gt;spelt&lt;/s&gt; [spent] my — my whole career believing in unions.&amp;nbsp; I’m not joking when I say that.&amp;nbsp; I’m honored to be considered the most pro-union president ever.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By the way, remember all the talk?&amp;nbsp; “Biden got elected, and he’s going to do a planned economy.&amp;nbsp; We’re going to collapse, and there’s going to be all this caving in.&amp;nbsp; Interest rates are going to go through the ceiling.”&amp;nbsp; Come on, man.&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I’m here to tell you it’s about increasing the strength of your unions, which it’s all about.&amp;nbsp; If you care about hardworking people, just give them a fair shot.&amp;nbsp; Everyone in America deserves a fair shot.&amp;nbsp; No guar- — a fair shot.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you care about the dignity of work — if you care about the dignity of work — and I mean it; it matters — the dignity of work, the way you’re treated, the decency.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I remember when my great-grandfather was one of the — only the second Catholic elected statewide to the state senate here in — in Pennsylvania.&amp;nbsp; And I remember they talked about when he — when they were running against him in 1906, they said, “Guess what?”&amp;nbsp; They said, “He’s a Molly Maguire.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You know what a Molly Maguire was?&amp;nbsp; Well, those of you who don’t, a Molly Maguire, back in the — in the old days, when we Irish and the Catholics came and then the Poles and others that were Catholic — when they came to the United States of America in the beginning, the 1840s and — late 1840s, they made their way down into Pennsylvania, a lot of them.&amp;nbsp; And there — there’s a tier in this — in the coal mines.&amp;nbsp; Those guys who got there last ended up being the last people in the coal mines.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But a lot of the English owned the coal mines.&amp;nbsp; And what they did was they’d really beat the hell out of the — the mostly Catholic population who was in the mines.&amp;nbsp; Not — not a joke.&amp;nbsp; Not a joke.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But there was a group.&amp;nbsp; They’re called the Molly Maguires.&amp;nbsp; And the Molly Maguires, if they’d find out the foreman who was taking advantage of an individual — and they’d literally kill him.&amp;nbsp; Not a joke.&amp;nbsp; And they’d bring his body up and put him on the doorstep of his family.&amp;nbsp; Kind of crude.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But I’ve got to admit, they accused my great-grandfather of being Molly — he wasn’t.&amp;nbsp; But we were so damn disappointed.&amp;nbsp; But, you know — (laughter) — I — that’s a joke.&amp;nbsp; That’s a joke.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Look, it’s about the dignity of work.&amp;nbsp; It’s about how you’re treated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And when I met with the IBEW when I started off this last campaign first, I said, “There’s two things that — asking of me.”&amp;nbsp; You’re — and I said, “Two things I’m asking of you.&amp;nbsp; One, you got to open up your unions to more women.”&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Not joke.&amp;nbsp; “And, two, to more minorities.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;You’ve done both that.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And guess what?&amp;nbsp; Instead of having the support of 30 percent of the American people, it’s now over 65 percent of the American people support the American union movement.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Look, it really is all about the dignity of work.&amp;nbsp; And there’s only — if you care about the dignity of work, there’s only one person you have a rational choice with this time, and that’s Kamala Harris.&amp;nbsp; Not a — (applause).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Kamala!&amp;nbsp; Kamala!&amp;nbsp; Kamala!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Let me tell you about this woman.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Kamala!&amp;nbsp; Kamala!&amp;nbsp; Kamala!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; I know her.&amp;nbsp; I trust her.&amp;nbsp; Not a joke.&amp;nbsp; I trust her.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Number two, the first decision I made the nomina- — as nominee in 2020 was selecting her as my vice president.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And, by the way, it was the single best decision I made as president of the United States of America.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And I was — I was watching something sent to me: When they asked Barack — they said Barack picked me as vice president because he knew I could be president.&amp;nbsp; Well, I know she’ll be a good president.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; I know it.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I’ve watched her when all the experts, foreign and domestic policy, would give us advice, then we’d sit alone in a room, and she has a backbone like a ramrod.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And she has the moral compass of a saint.&amp;nbsp; This woman knows what she’s doing.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Folks, I promise you, if you elect Kamala Harris as president, it will be the best decision you will have ever made.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And Kamala believes, as I do, that unions are the spine of this economy.&amp;nbsp; She’ll be a historic pro-union president.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So, folks, we got one more job to do together.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Let me ask you: Are you ready to fight?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Yeah!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Are you ready to win?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Yeah!&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Are you ready to elect Kamala Harris our next president of the United States of America?&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, in the process, are you ready to make Donald Trump a loser again?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Yeah!&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; I’ve never been more optimistic about America’s future.&amp;nbsp; We have to remember who we are.&amp;nbsp; We’re the United States of America.&amp;nbsp; There’s nothing, nothing — I mean this from the bottom of my heart — there’s nothing beyond our capacity — nothing — when we do it together.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And that means elect my friend, our great vice president, president of the United States.&amp;nbsp; Kamala Harris.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Good afternoon, Pittsburgh!&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Joe!&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&amp;nbsp; Thank you, Joe!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; It is good to be in the house of labor.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; It is good to be in the house of labor.&amp;nbsp; And it is good to be back at IBEW Local 5.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And can we please give it up again for our president, Joe Biden?&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Now, I don’t have to tell the brothers and sisters of labor that you really get to know somebody when you’re in the middle of a fight, when times are hard, when the forces are mighty, when people don’t believe something can get done, and they have a thousand excuses for why it can’t get done.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And I have spent more time with this extraordinary human being when the cameras were not in the room, when the stakes were high, when the heat was intense.&amp;nbsp; And Joe Biden has always stood with the workers of America and labor unions of America.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Always.&amp;nbsp; Always.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;I’ve been with him when he’ll bring folks into the Oval Office.&amp;nbsp; And you know how Joe can get sometimes.&amp;nbsp; He doesn’t spare words.&amp;nbsp; It’s good that sometimes the cameras are not in the room when he has those conversations.&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because the thing about the Joe Biden I know — and I know you know, because he has been a frain- — friend of labor for so long, for his whole life — Joe Biden can be quite impatient, and that’s a good thing for that kind of leader.&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&amp;nbsp; Quite impatient.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And I say to all of the friends here, the press that’s in the room: History will show what we here know.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; Joe Biden has been one of the most transformative presidents in the United States that we have ever witnessed.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And it comes from his heart.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, you know, Joe and I talk a lot about the fact that we are so proud to be the most pro-union administration in America’s history, and it’s thanks to your leadership.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And, as we know, Joe has still got a lot of work to do, so let’s — let’s also understand that.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;So, I want to thank all the incredible leaders who are here today, including the governor, Shapiro; Lieutenant Governor Davis; Senator Casey, who we will reelect this November — (applause); Mayor Gainey; President Shuler; President Cooper; all the leaders of labor who are here; all the union members who are here.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;So, I’ll just get right to a few points.&amp;nbsp; I love Labor Day.&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&amp;nbsp; I love celebrating Labor Day.&amp;nbsp; And Pittsburgh, of course, is a cradle of the American labor movement.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; It is the birthplace of the AFL, headquarters of the Steelworkers, home to Fire Fighters Local 1, and, of course, the historic IBEW Local 5.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;For more than 150 years, the brothers and sisters of labor have helped lead the fight for fair pay, better benefits, and safe working conditions, and every person in our nation has benefited from that work.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You know, everywhere I go, I tell people, “You may not be a union member, but you better thank unions for that five-day work week.&amp;nbsp; Thank unions for sick leave.&amp;nbsp; Thank unions for paid family leave.&amp;nbsp; Thank unions for your vacation time.”&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because when union wages go up, everybody’s wages go up.&amp;nbsp; When union workplaces are safer, all workplaces are safer.&amp;nbsp; When unions are strong, America is strong.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And we are clear: Not only has Pittsburgh shaped the history of America’s labor movement, today you are also shaping its future.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In 2021, with my dear friend, the Secretary, Marty Walsh, who the president appointed to be Secretary of Labor, he and I hosted a meeting right here in this Local, and it was part of the White House Labor Task Force that I lead.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That day, we met with a group of computer programmers who were working to form a union.&amp;nbsp; One month later, they signed their contract and became the first — one of the first technology unions in our nation — (applause) — standing on the shoulder of all those who have been here and fought the good fight.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;So, Pittsburgh, I r- — I remind us of that to say, together, we are fighting to build an economy that works for all working people.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And that has always been the vision of the labor movement.&amp;nbsp; And that is the vision of our campaign.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;You know, in this election, there are two very different visions for our nation: one, ours, focused on the future; the other focused on the past.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; We fight for the future.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; We fight for a future of dignity, respect, and opportunity for all people.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We fight knowing it’s some backward thinking for those folks to have been suggesting for years that the — the measure of the strength of a leader is based on who you beat down.&amp;nbsp; You know, that’s the stuff they’re pushing — that the measure of the strength of a leader is based on who you beat down — when we know the true measure of the strength of a leader is based on who you lift up — (applause) — who you lift up.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;Do you fight for workers?&amp;nbsp; Do you fight for families?&amp;nbsp; Do you fight for those who must be seen and heard and deserve the dignity that comes with hard work?&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That’s what we fight for.&amp;nbsp; And when you know what you stand for, you know what to fight for.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;So, we’re 64 days out from this election.&amp;nbsp; (Laughter.)&amp;nbsp; Ballots in Pennsylvania will start dropping in 14 days — (applause) — 14 days.&amp;nbsp; And this election is, as much as anything else, a fight for the promise of America — (applause) — for the promise of America.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We love our country.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; We love our country.&amp;nbsp; And we know it is one of the highest forms of patriotism to fight for the ideals of our country, and that’s what this election is about, and about the promise of America.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And I don’t need to tell unions what the promise looks like.&amp;nbsp; It’s what you do every day.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But as we fight to move forward, Donald Trump is trying to pull us backward, including back to a time before workers had the freedom to organize.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE MEMBER:&amp;nbsp; He’s going to jail!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE MEMBER:&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Well, the courts will handle that, and we will handle November.&amp;nbsp; How about that?&amp;nbsp; (Laughter and applause.)&amp;nbsp; We’ll handle November.&amp;nbsp; Let the courts handle that other thing.&amp;nbsp; But we’re not going back.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back.&amp;nbsp; And —&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; And one of the ways — one of the ways we’re going to guarantee we don’t go back is that we remember.&amp;nbsp; Right?&amp;nbsp; It is important to remember what that was and what it is.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Remember, as president, Donald Trump blocked overtime benefits for millions of workers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; He opposed efforts to raise the minimum wage.&amp;nbsp; As the president said, he appointed union busters to the National Labor Relations Board.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; And don’t forget, he supported so-called right-to-work laws.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; And if Donald Trump were to be reelected, he intends to give more tax cuts to billionaires and big corporations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; He intends to cut Social Security and Medicare.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; He wants to impose what, in effect, would be a national sales tax.&amp;nbsp; I call it the “Trump national sales tax” on everyday products and basic necessities that would cost a typical American family — the economists have said this — almost $4,000 a year.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; He intends to repeal the Affordable Care Act&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Booo —&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; — and take us back to what we remember — because it wasn’t that long ago — was a time when insurance companies could deny people with preexisting conditions.&amp;nbsp; You remember what that was?&amp;nbsp; Children with asthma.&amp;nbsp; Breast cancer survivors.&amp;nbsp; Grandparents with diabetes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Well, look, America has tried those failed policies before, and we are not going back.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; We are not going back.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&amp;nbsp; We’re not going back!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; And instead — and instead, we fight for a future where no person has to go broke just because they get sick.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And so, building on the work of President Joe Biden and I and the work we have done in the White House, we will continue to strengthen the Affordable Care Act and make prescription drugs affordable for all Americans.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We — (applause) — we — we fight for a future where every worker has the freedom to organize.&amp;nbsp; And we will pass the PRO Act and end union busting once and for all, and Bob Casey will help us do that.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We — we see and know and fight for a future where every person has the opportunity not just to get by but to get ahead.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And so, we will continue to build what I call an “opportunity economy” so that every American has an opportunity to buy a home or start a business or build intergenerational wealth and have a future that matches their dreams and ambitions and aspirations.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Because, of course, that’s the nature of who we are as Americans.&amp;nbsp; We have dreams.&amp;nbsp; We can see what is possible, unburdened by what has been.&amp;nbsp; We have aspirations.&amp;nbsp; We have ambitions.&amp;nbsp; And the system that is a good system is one that supports that and allows people the opportunity to go where they can see and imagine themselves to be.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;That’s what I’m talking about when I talk about an opportunity economy.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;We fight for a future where every senior can retire with dignity, and so we will continue to defend Social Security and Medicare and pensions.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp; And pensions.&amp;nbsp; And pensions.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And we will continue to strengthen America’s manufacturing sector.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And on that point, the president mentioned it, U.S. Steel is an historic American company, and it is vital for our nation to maintain strong American steel companies.&amp;nbsp; And I couldn’t agree more with President Biden, U.S. Steel should remain American-owned and American-operated.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And I will always have the back of America’s steelworkers — (applause) — and all of America’s workers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;So, friends, 64 days until the most [important] election of our lives, and probably one of the most important in the life of our nation, truly.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And we know this is going to be a tight race to the very end.&amp;nbsp; It’s going to be a tight race to the very end.&amp;nbsp; So, let’s not pay too much attention to those polls.&amp;nbsp; Because as unions and labor knows best, we know what it’s like to be the underdog.&amp;nbsp; And we are the underdog in this race, and we have some hard work, then, ahead of us.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;But here’s the beauty of us in this room: We like hard work.&amp;nbsp; Hard work is good work.&amp;nbsp; Hard work is joyful work.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;And so, in this fight, I will continue to count on the strength, the determination, and the hard work of the leaders in this room to knock on doors, to get folks to the polls, and — bluntly put, because the people in here do it — to help us win Pennsylvania.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;So, today, I ask, are you ready to make your voices heard?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Yes!&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Do we believe in freedom?&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Yes!&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Do we believe in opportunity?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Yes!&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; Do we believe in the promise of America?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Yes!&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; And are we ready to fight for it?&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; Yes!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; And when we fight —&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;AUDIENCE:&amp;nbsp; We win!&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;THE VICE PRESIDENT:&amp;nbsp; — we win.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;God bless you.&amp;nbsp; God bless America.&amp;nbsp; (Applause.)&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; 6:27 P.M. EDT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <link>https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/09/02/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-at-a-campaign-event-pittsburgh-pa/</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.whitehouse.gov/briefing-room/speeches-remarks/2024/09/02/remarks-by-president-biden-and-vice-president-harris-at-a-campaign-event-pittsburgh-pa/</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 21:47:59 GMT</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
